Original Text,NER for Original,Generated Summaries,NER for Generated
"As Chancellor George Osborne announced all English state schools will become academies, the Welsh Government continues to reject the model here.","[('Wales', 'GPE'), ('England', 'GPE'), ('Osborne', 'PERSON'), (""Offa's Dyke"", 'ORG'), ('the Welsh Government', 'ORG'), ('English', 'LANGUAGE'), ('the school day', 'DATE'), ('school hours', 'TIME'), ('more than 2,000', 'CARDINAL'), ('England', 'GPE'), (""the Welsh Government's"", 'ORG')]",The chancellor's plan to extend the school day to all state schools in England and make them academies will have a significant impact on schools in Wales.,"[('England', 'GPE'), ('Wales', 'GPE')]"
"Discounted bus tickets for 16 to 18 year olds will be rolled out in Greater Manchester, it has been announced.","[('Up to 100,000', 'CARDINAL'), ('The Young Persons 16-18', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('September', 'DATE'), ('Andy Burnham', 'PERSON'), ('Transport for Greater Manchester', 'ORG'), ('Metrolink', 'FAC'), ('Hajrah Ahmed', 'PERSON'), ('17', 'DATE'), ('Manchester College', 'ORG'), ('Openshaw', 'PERSON'), ('Cheetham Hill', 'GPE'), ('every day', 'DATE'), ('100', 'MONEY'), ('the next year', 'DATE'), ('Burnham', 'PERSON'), ('April', 'DATE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Burnham', 'PERSON'), ('Greater Manchester Travelcards Ltd', 'ORG'), ('50%', 'PERCENT')]","Young people in Greater Manchester are to get half-price bus tickets as part of a scheme to help them get on in life, it has been announced.","[('Greater Manchester', 'GPE')]"
"""The winner takes it all, the loser has to fall...""","[('Middlesbrough', 'GPE'), ('Brighton', 'GPE'), ('Saturday', 'DATE'), ('the Premier League', 'ORG'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Boro', 'PERSON'), ('Seagulls', 'ORG'), ('BBC Sport', 'ORG'), ('five', 'CARDINAL'), ('years past', 'DATE'), ('Championship', 'EVENT'), ('season', 'DATE'), ('Liverpool', 'GPE'), ('Arsenal', 'ORG'), ('1989', 'DATE'), ('Liverpool', 'GPE'), ('First Division', 'ORG'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('season', 'DATE'), ('Arsenal', 'PERSON'), ('Anfield', 'GPE'), ('Reds', 'ORG'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('English', 'NORP'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Arsenal', 'ORG'), ('1-0', 'CARDINAL'), ('Alan Smith', 'PERSON'), ('ITV', 'ORG'), ('Brian Moore', 'PERSON'), ('Smith', 'PERSON'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON')]","The final day of the Championship season has the potential to be one of the most dramatic in the club's history, with promotion and relegation all on the line.","[('Championship', 'EVENT'), ('one', 'CARDINAL')]"
"Support for vulnerable children in England is at risk as funding ebbs away, according to a charity's analysis of government figures.","[('35%', 'PERCENT'), ('five years', 'DATE'), (""Barnardo's"", 'ORG'), ('England', 'GPE'), ('the Department for Education', 'ORG'), ('£1.2bn', 'MONEY'), ('2010-11', 'DATE'), ('an estimated £740m', 'MONEY'), ('2014-15', 'DATE'), ('year', 'DATE'), ('hundreds', 'CARDINAL'), ('England', 'GPE'), ('England', 'GPE'), ('about 2,800', 'CARDINAL'), (""Barnardo's"", 'ORG'), ('190', 'CARDINAL')]","Hundreds of children's centres in England are facing closure as a result of cuts in funding, says a charity which runs some of the country's largest centres.","[('Hundreds', 'CARDINAL'), ('England', 'GPE')]"
The Philippines has submitted evidence to a UN tribunal hearing its case against China's territorial claims in the South China Sea.,"[('China', 'GPE'), ('a day', 'DATE'), ('Philippine', 'NORP'), ('Chinese', 'NORP'), ('China', 'GPE'), ('the South China Sea', 'LOC'), ('Philippines', 'GPE'), ('Vietnam', 'GPE'), ('Brunei', 'GPE'), ('Malaysia', 'GPE'), ('Taiwan', 'GPE'), ('Philippines', 'GPE'), ('China', 'GPE'), ('the United Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea', 'LAW'), ('January', 'DATE'), ('Philippines', 'GPE'), ('UN', 'ORG'), ('Permanent Court of Arbitration', 'ORG'), ('the end of 2015', 'DATE'), ('Sunday', 'DATE'), ('Philippine', 'NORP'), ('Albert del Rosario', 'PERSON'), ('more than 40', 'CARDINAL'), ('nearly 4,000', 'CARDINAL')]","The Philippines has submitted more than 4,000 pages of evidence to a UN tribunal considering its case against China's claims in the South China Sea.","[('Philippines', 'GPE'), ('more than 4,000', 'CARDINAL'), ('UN', 'ORG'), ('China', 'GPE'), ('the South China Sea', 'LOC')]"
"When several dozen Georgian Orthodox priests led tens of thousands of people on a violent attack against a small group of gay rights activists in Tbilisi earlier this year, much of the rest of the country was horrified, writes journalist Paul Rimple, who has been based in the country for 10 years.","[('Georgians', 'NORP'), ('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Georgia', 'GPE'), ('Russia', 'GPE'), ('Georgian', 'NORP'), ('Georgia', 'GPE'), ('Georgia Direct', 'ORG'), ('Caucasus', 'LOC'), ('Georgians', 'NORP'), ('Tbilisi', 'GPE'), ('17 May', 'DATE'), ('Church', 'ORG'), ('Georgia', 'GPE'), ('Georgia', 'GPE'), ('Christianity', 'NORP'), ('337AD', 'DATE'), ('Georgians', 'NORP'), ('Ghengis Khan', 'PERSON'), ('Tamerlane', 'PERSON'), ('Soviets', 'NORP'), ('1917', 'DATE'), ('2,455', 'CARDINAL'), ('Georgia', 'GPE'), ('the mid-1980s', 'DATE'), ('80', 'CARDINAL')]","In our series of letters from African journalists, film-maker and columnist Farai Sevenzo looks at the role of the Church in the Georgian capital, Tbilisi.","[('African', 'NORP'), ('Farai Sevenzo', 'PERSON'), ('Church', 'ORG'), ('Georgian', 'NORP'), ('Tbilisi', 'GPE')]"
"The funeral has been held for the former Antiques Roadshow TV host Hugh Scully, who died at the age of 72.","[('Antiques Roadshow', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Mawnan Smith', 'FAC'), ('Falmouth', 'GPE'), ('Scully', 'PERSON'), ('BBC', 'ORG'), ('1965', 'DATE'), ('BBC', 'ORG'), ('Nationwide', 'ORG'), ('Antiques Roadshow', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Arthur Negus', 'PERSON'), ('1981', 'DATE'), ('the Antiques Roadshow', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Scully', 'PERSON'), ('BBC', 'ORG'), ('Nationwide', 'ORG'), ('Antiques Roadshow', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Arthur Negus', 'PERSON'), ('1981', 'DATE'), ('BBC One', 'ORG'), ('2000', 'DATE'), ('Charles Scully', 'PERSON'), ('BBC', 'ORG'), ('Nationwide', 'ORG'), ('Sue Lawley', 'PERSON'), ('Scully', 'PERSON')]","The funeral of Antiques Roadshow presenter John Scully has taken place in the Cornwall village where he was born and grew up, his family has said.","[('Antiques Roadshow', 'ORG'), ('John Scully', 'PERSON'), ('Cornwall', 'GPE')]"
League One side Gillingham have signed Tottenham Hotspur defender Connor Ogilvie on a six-month loan deal.,"[('Ogilvie', 'PERSON'), ('21', 'DATE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Spurs', 'ORG'), ('the last two seasons', 'DATE'), ('League Two Stevenage', 'ORG'), ('England', 'GPE'), ('18', 'CARDINAL'), ('Boro', 'PERSON'), ('last season', 'DATE'), ('Ogilvie', 'PERSON'), ('Connor', 'PERSON'), ('Tottenham', 'ORG'), ('Gillingham', 'PERSON'), ('Ady Pennock', 'PERSON')]","League One side Gillingham have signed Tottenham Hotspur midfielder Connor Ogilvie on a two-year deal for an undisclosed fee, subject to international clearance.","[('League One', 'ORG'), ('Gillingham', 'ORG'), ('Tottenham Hotspur', 'ORG'), ('Connor Ogilvie', 'PERSON'), ('two-year', 'DATE')]"
Wasps won a sixth straight Premiership game with a bonus-point victory over Harlequins at the Ricoh Arena.,"[('20 minutes', 'TIME'), ('Jake Cooper-Woolley', 'PERSON'), ('Christian Wade', 'PERSON'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Luke Wallace', 'PERSON'), ('Quins', 'PERSON'), ('Nathan Hughes', 'PERSON'), ('21-5', 'CARDINAL'), ('Thomas Young', 'PERSON'), ('fourth', 'ORDINAL'), ('Siale Piutau', 'PERSON'), ('Brendan Macken', 'PERSON'), (""Dai Young's"", 'PERSON'), ('Wasps', 'ORG'), ('15-9', 'DATE'), ('Sale', 'ORG'), ('2 January', 'DATE'), ('third', 'ORDINAL'), ('Harlequins', 'ORG'), ('Saracens', 'PERSON'), (""Valentine's Day"", 'DATE'), ('Wasps', 'ORG'), ('recent weeks', 'DATE'), ('Cooper-Woolley', 'PERSON'), ('Charles Piutau', 'PERSON'), ('Wade', 'PERSON'), ('Hughes', 'PERSON'), ('third', 'ORDINAL'), (""Charlie Walker's"", 'PERSON'), ('Quins', 'PERSON'), ('a nervy few minutes', 'TIME')]",Wasps continued their 100% start to the Premiership season with a bonus-point win over Harlequins at the Ricoh Arena in Coventry.,"[('Wasps', 'ORG'), ('100%', 'PERCENT'), ('Premiership', 'ORG'), ('Harlequins', 'ORG'), ('the Ricoh Arena', 'FAC'), ('Coventry', 'GPE')]"
"Construction output fell by 2.1% in May compared with a month earlier, official figures have shown.","[('The Office for National Statistics', 'ORG'), ('ONS', 'ORG'), ('European Union', 'ORG'), ('EU', 'ORG'), ('April', 'DATE'), ('2.8%', 'PERCENT'), ('6%', 'PERCENT'), ('1.9%', 'PERCENT'), ('June', 'DATE'), ('ONS', 'ORG'), ('3.2%', 'PERCENT'), ('May', 'DATE'), ('0.1%', 'PERCENT'), ('April', 'DATE'), ('February 2014', 'DATE'), ('every month this year', 'DATE'), ('February', 'DATE'), ('May 2016', 'DATE'), ('April', 'DATE'), ('the start of 2015', 'DATE'), ('ONS', 'ORG'), ('1.9%', 'PERCENT'), ('May 2015', 'DATE'), ('ONS', 'ORG'), ('UK', 'GPE'), ('0.4%', 'PERCENT'), ('the three months to the end of March', 'DATE')]","UK construction output fell 3.2% in May compared with the same month last year, the biggest fall since February 2014, official figures show.","[('UK', 'GPE'), ('3.2%', 'PERCENT'), ('May', 'DATE'), ('the same month last year', 'DATE'), ('February 2014', 'DATE')]"
Eritrea has accused Ethiopia of launching an attack at the countries' heavily-militarised border.,"[('Ethiopia', 'GPE'), ('Tsorona', 'GPE'), ('Ethiopian', 'NORP'), ('2000', 'DATE'), ('BBC', 'ORG'), ('Ethiopia', 'GPE'), ('Emmanuel Igunza', 'PERSON'), ('Eritrea', 'GPE'), ('Ethiopia', 'GPE'), ('decades', 'DATE'), ('recent months', 'DATE'), ('Eritrea', 'GPE'), ('Isaias Afwerki', 'PERSON'), ('25 years', 'DATE'), ('Ethiopia', 'GPE'), ('Eritrea', 'GPE'), ('Earlier this year', 'DATE'), ('Ethiopia', 'GPE'), ('Hailemariam Desalegn', 'PERSON')]",Ethiopia and Eritrea have been reported to have exchanged fire along their border for the first time since a peace deal was signed in 2000.,"[('Ethiopia', 'GPE'), ('Eritrea', 'GPE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('2000', 'DATE')]"
Wales Under-20 ran in eight tries to beat Samoa and secure their first win of the World Rugby U20 Championship in Georgia.,"[('Samoa', 'GPE'), ('Wales', 'GPE'), (""Jared Rosser's"", 'PERSON'), ('Aled Ward', 'PERSON'), ('Sean Moore', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Shane Lewis-Hughes', 'PERSON'), ('Wales', 'GPE'), ('Alexander Pohla-Murray', 'PERSON'), ('Setu Enoka', 'PERSON'), ('Samoa', 'GPE'), ('Dane Blacker', 'PERSON'), ('Will Griffiths', 'PERSON'), ('Joe Goodchild', 'PERSON'), ('Wales', 'GPE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Australia', 'GPE'), ('England', 'GPE'), ('Pool A', 'GPE'), ('Wales', 'GPE'), (""Jason Strange's"", 'PERSON'), ('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('U20 Trophy', 'EVENT'), ('next year', 'DATE'), ('Ireland', 'GPE'), ('New Zealand', 'GPE'), ('Wales', 'GPE'), ('69-3', 'CARDINAL'), ('Kiwis', 'NORP'), ('Scotland', 'GPE'), ('fifth', 'ORDINAL'), ('eighth', 'ORDINAL'), ('Tuesday', 'DATE'), ('13 June', 'DATE'), ('Wales U20', 'ORG'), ('Phil Jones', 'PERSON'), ('Ospreys', 'ORG'), ('Jared Rosser', 'PERSON'), ('Newport Gwent Dragons', 'GPE'), ('Ioan Nicholas', 'PERSON'), ('Scarlets', 'ORG'), ('Owen Lane', 'PERSON'), ('Cardiff Blues', 'ORG'), ('Joe Goodchild', 'PERSON'), ('Newport Gwent Dragons', 'ORG'), ('Ben Jones', 'PERSON'), ('Cardiff Blues', 'ORG'), ('Reuben Morgan', 'PERSON')]",Wales Under-20s secured their first win of the World Rugby U20 Championship with a bonus-point victory over Samoa in Johannesburg.,"[('Wales Under-20s', 'ORG'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('the World Rugby U20 Championship', 'EVENT'), ('Samoa', 'GPE'), ('Johannesburg', 'GPE')]"
A man has appeared in court charged in connection with an armed robbery at a post office in Cumbria.,"[('Mark Mercer', 'PERSON'), ('47', 'DATE'), ('Toll Bar Houses', 'ORG'), ('Workington', 'GPE'), ('1,530', 'CARDINAL'), ('Maryport Post Office', 'ORG'), ('Monday', 'DATE'), (""Carlisle Magistrates' Court"", 'ORG'), ('Mercer', 'PERSON'), ('24-year-old', 'DATE'), ('14 March', 'DATE')]",A man has appeared in court charged with robbery and firearms offences following a raid on a post office in Cumbria that left a woman in hospital.,"[('Cumbria', 'GPE')]"
Shares in the baby formula milk firm Bellamy have plunged after a warning that new import regulations in China will cut into revenues.,"[('Australian', 'NORP'), ('more than 40%', 'PERCENT'), ('China', 'GPE'), ('Food and Drug Administration', 'ORG'), ('China', 'GPE'), ('Australia', 'GPE'), ('New Zealand', 'GPE'), ('Chinese', 'NORP'), ('Chinese', 'NORP'), ('recent years', 'DATE'), ('December 2017', 'DATE'), (""Bellamy's"", 'ORG'), ('China', 'GPE'), ('the Australian Securities Exchange', 'ORG')]",Shares in infant formula maker Bellamy's have fallen sharply after the company said that new regulations in China would hit sales in the world's largest breastfeeding market.,"[(""Bellamy's"", 'ORG'), ('China', 'GPE')]"
"A pair of Vietnamese fraternal twins have been confirmed to have different fathers, a local genetic association has told the BBC.","[('Le Dinh Luong', 'PERSON'), ('the Hanoi-based Vietnam Genetic Association', 'ORG'), ('100%', 'PERCENT'), ('only less than 10', 'CARDINAL'), ('BBC', 'ORG'), ('Nga Pham', 'PERSON'), ('Vietnamese', 'NORP'), ('earlier this month', 'DATE'), ('one', 'CARDINAL')]","Vietnam has confirmed for the first time that a set of twins were born to the same mother but with different fathers, a genetic expert has said.","[('Vietnam', 'GPE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')]"
"Iran's President Mahmoud Ahmadinejad has sacked Health Minister Marziyeh Vahid Dastjerdi, the sole woman in his cabinet, state television reports.","[('Dastjerdi', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('30-year', 'DATE'), ('Islamic', 'NORP'), ('Ahmadinejad', 'PERSON'), ('Islamic', 'NORP'), ('Dastjerdi', 'PERSON'), ('the first half of the current year', 'DATE'), ('the Central Bank', 'ORG'), ('$2.5bn (£1.6bn', 'MONEY')]","Iranian President Mahmoud Ahmadinejad has sacked Health Minister Nour Dastjerdi, who was the country's first female health minister, state media report.","[('Iranian', 'NORP'), ('Mahmoud Ahmadinejad', 'PERSON'), ('Nour Dastjerdi', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')]"
A ceremony has been held to mark the start of work to rebuild a historic railway station in Royal Deeside which was destroyed by fire.,"[('The Old Royal Station', 'FAC'), ('Ballater', 'GPE'), ('May 2015', 'DATE'), ('the Royal Family', 'ORG'), ('Balmoral', 'GPE'), ('December', 'DATE')]","Work has begun to rebuild a railway station in Aberdeenshire that was destroyed in a fire two years ago, the Scottish government has announced.","[('Aberdeenshire', 'GPE'), ('two years ago', 'DATE'), ('Scottish', 'NORP')]"
China's internet watchdog has banned web users from posting messages under the names of famous people.,"[('The Cyberspace Administration of China', 'ORG'), ('CAC', 'ORG'), ('Barack Obama', 'PERSON'), ('Chinese', 'NORP'), ('CAC', 'ORG'), ('Communist Party', 'ORG'), ('Xi Jinping', 'PERSON'), ('CAC', 'ORG'), ('1 March', 'DATE'), ('CAC', 'ORG'), ('Xu Feng', 'PERSON')]","China's internet regulator has announced a crackdown on web users who use nicknames such as ""Mr China"" or ""Mr America"".. Xie Zhiyong, a Beijing-based internet expert, explains.","[('China', 'GPE'), ('China', 'PERSON'), ('America', 'PERSON'), ('Xie Zhiyong', 'PERSON'), ('Beijing-based', 'NORP')]"
Two men who shot dead a mother-of-two by mistake have been jailed for life for her murder.,"[('Hayley Pointon', 'PERSON'), ('30', 'DATE'), ('Hinckley', 'GPE'), ('Leicestershire', 'GPE'), ('Nigel Barwell', 'PERSON'), ('February 2013', 'DATE'), ('Aaron Power', 'PERSON'), ('25', 'DATE'), ('Aaron Newman', 'PERSON'), ('24', 'DATE'), ('Coventry', 'GPE'), ('31 years', 'DATE'), ('Pointon', 'PERSON'), ('Coventry', 'GPE'), ('eight-week', 'DATE'), ('Leicester Crown Court', 'ORG'), ('Barwell', 'PERSON'), ('Pointon', 'PERSON'), ('King', 'PERSON'), ('Hayley', 'PERSON'), ('Kerry Pointon', 'PERSON')]","Two men have been jailed for life for the ""cold-blooded murder"" of a woman who was shot dead in a ""planned killing"" at her boyfriend's home.","[('Two', 'CARDINAL')]"
Jay Donnelly's winning goal two minutes into the first period of extra-time secured Cliftonville's passage into a fourth consecutive League Cup decider.,"[('Reds', 'ORG'), ('the last three seasons', 'DATE'), ('13 February', 'DATE'), ('Donnelly', 'PERSON'), (""Stephen Garrett's"", 'PERSON'), ('Warrenpoint', 'ORG'), ('Mark Clarke', 'PERSON'), ('Liam Bagnall', 'PERSON'), ('Barry Gray', 'PERSON'), ('Reds', 'ORG'), ('Tomas Cosgrove', 'PERSON'), ('Stephen Garrett', 'PERSON'), ('the 77th minute', 'TIME'), ('Clarke', 'PERSON'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('James Knowles', 'PERSON'), ('Donnelly', 'PERSON'), ('19th', 'ORDINAL'), ('Reds', 'ORG'), ('ninth', 'ORDINAL'), ('season', 'DATE'), ('Donnelly', 'PERSON'), ('Gray', 'PERSON'), ('Bagnall', 'PERSON'), ('second', 'ORDINAL')]",John Donnelly scored a late winner as 10-man Crusaders beat Warrenpoint Town to book their place in the Irish Cup quarter-finals.,"[('John Donnelly', 'PERSON'), ('Crusaders', 'PRODUCT'), ('Warrenpoint Town', 'FAC'), ('the Irish Cup', 'EVENT')]"
"On 24 July 1936, the talking clock spoke for the first time.","[('24 July 2016', 'DATE'), ('00:02 BST', 'TIME'), ('80-year', 'DATE'), ('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('Ethel Jane Cain', 'PERSON'), ('Pat Simmons', 'PERSON'), ('Brian Cobby', 'PERSON'), ('Sara Mendes da Costa', 'PERSON')]","The talking clock has been celebrating its 80th anniversary with a special performance at the Royal Albert Hall in London on Thursday night, with a performance by Sara Mendes da Costa.","[('80th anniversary', 'DATE'), ('the Royal Albert Hall', 'FAC'), ('London', 'GPE'), ('Thursday night', 'TIME'), ('Sara Mendes da Costa', 'PERSON')]"
"Thousands of Scots face unfair working practices which leave them in ""desperate and miserable situations"", according to a report.","[('Citizens Advice Scotland', 'ORG'), ('CAS', 'ORG'), ('more than 46,500', 'CARDINAL'), ('last year', 'DATE'), ('5.5%', 'PERCENT'), ('the previous year', 'DATE'), ('CAS', 'ORG'), ('Fair Enough?', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Scotland', 'GPE'), ('Employment Tribunal', 'ORG'), ('Employment Commission', 'ORG'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), (""six months'"", 'DATE')]","A charity has called for an end to the use of employment tribunals in Scotland, after a rise in the number of cases it dealt with.","[('Scotland', 'GPE')]"
The Football League is slowly cranking itself up to full speed with Saturday's second round of games done and dusted.,"[('BBC Sport', 'ORG'), ('day', 'DATE'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Fulham', 'GPE'), ('Brighton', 'GPE'), ('Nottingham Forest', 'ORG'), ('last Friday', 'DATE'), ('English', 'NORP'), ('new season', 'DATE'), ('Brighton', 'GPE'), ('Championship', 'EVENT'), ('Sam Baldock', 'PERSON'), ('Tomer Hemed', 'PERSON'), ('Seagulls', 'ORG'), ('2-1', 'CARDINAL'), ('Fulham', 'ORG'), ('Craven Cottage', 'FAC'), ('Championship', 'ORG'), ('Chris Hughton', 'PERSON'), ('BBC Sussex', 'ORG'), ('Carlisle', 'GPE'), ('Cambridge', 'GPE'), ('Another season', 'DATE'), ('6,354', 'CARDINAL'), ('Brunton Park', 'FAC'), ('Saturday', 'DATE'), ('Carlisle', 'GPE'), ('Cambridge', 'GPE')]","It's been another busy day in English football, with Carlisle and Cambridge sharing the spoils in an FA Cup fourth-round tie and Brighton beating Fulham to go top of the Championship.","[('English', 'LANGUAGE'), ('Carlisle', 'ORG'), ('Cambridge', 'GPE'), ('FA Cup', 'EVENT'), ('Brighton', 'GPE'), ('Fulham', 'PERSON'), ('Championship', 'EVENT')]"
Hundreds of bird watchers have travelled to Norfolk in the hope of seeing a bird that has been spotted for only the second time in the UK.,"[('Marcus Nash', 'PERSON'), ('Burnham Overy', 'GPE'), ('Sunday', 'DATE'), ('morning', 'TIME'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('Alps', 'LOC'), ('Pyrenees', 'LOC'), ('Nash', 'PERSON'), ('Alps', 'LOC'), ('the day', 'DATE'), ('Monday', 'DATE'), ('Paul Stancliffe', 'PERSON'), ('the British Trust for Ornithology', 'ORG'), ('the Shetland Isles', 'LOC'), ('2008', 'DATE'), ('Stancliffe', 'PERSON'), ('David North', 'PERSON'), ('Norfolk Wildlife Trust', 'ORG'), ('North', 'PERSON')]","A rare bird of prey has been spotted in Norfolk for the first time in the UK, according to an amateur ornithologist who spotted it on a footpath.","[('Norfolk', 'GPE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('UK', 'GPE')]"
"The Lawn Tennis Association plans to hand out 10,000 free racquets and offer 10,000 free junior tennis courses in an attempt to unearth stars of the future.","[('LTA', 'ORG'), ('Davis Cup', 'EVENT'), ('50', 'CARDINAL'), ('Britain', 'GPE'), ('LTA', 'ORG'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Andy Murray', 'PERSON'), ('Britain', 'GPE'), ('the Davis Cup', 'EVENT'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('1936', 'DATE'), ('Belgium', 'GPE'), ('Ghent', 'GPE'), ('November', 'DATE'), ('Davis Cup', 'ORG'), ('Leon Smith', 'PERSON'), ('1,000', 'CARDINAL'), ('LTA', 'ORG'), ('Davis Cup', 'EVENT'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Japan', 'GPE'), ('March', 'DATE')]",The Lawn Tennis Association (LTA) has announced it will offer free lessons in tennis to children as part of its celebrations of winning the Davis Cup.,"[('The Lawn Tennis Association', 'ORG'), ('LTA', 'ORG'), ('the Davis Cup', 'EVENT')]"
Two New Zealand radio presenters have been suspended after broadcasting a phone call from Ben Stokes' mum when she believed she was off air.,"[('Deborah Stokes', 'PERSON'), ('England', 'GPE'), ('World Twenty20', 'EVENT'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Radio Hauraki', 'ORG'), ('Stokes', 'PERSON'), ('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('England', 'GPE'), ('Stokes', 'PERSON'), ('Carlos Braithwaite', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('West Indies', 'GPE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('World T20', 'EVENT'), (""Stokes'"", 'PERSON'), ('Deborah', 'PERSON'), ('New Zealand', 'GPE'), ('Ben', 'PERSON'), ('12', 'DATE'), ('Jeremy Wells', 'PERSON'), ('Matt Heath', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('New Zealand', 'GPE')]","The mother of Ben Stokes called into a New Zealand radio station to complain about what she called a ""personal attack"" by two presenters.","[('Ben Stokes', 'PERSON'), ('New Zealand', 'GPE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')]"
"China's economy grew by 6.9% in the first quarter of 2017, according to official figures.","[('the same three months', 'DATE'), ('the previous year', 'DATE'), ('Last month', 'DATE'), ('China', 'GPE'), ('this year', 'DATE'), ('6.5%', 'PERCENT'), ('6.7%', 'PERCENT'), ('2016', 'DATE'), ('China', 'GPE'), ('National Bureau of Statistics', 'ORG'), ('the second half of last year', 'DATE'), ('2017', 'DATE'), ('February', 'DATE'), ('10.9%', 'PERCENT'), ('the previous year', 'DATE'), ('Chinese', 'NORP'), ('Beijing', 'GPE'), ('China', 'GPE')]","China's economy grew 6.6% in the first three months of 2017, official figures show, up from 6.4% the previous quarter.","[('China', 'GPE'), ('6.6%', 'PERCENT'), ('the first three months of 2017', 'DATE'), ('6.4%', 'PERCENT'), ('the previous quarter', 'DATE')]"
"The number of migrants and refugees crossing into Europe by land and sea this year illegally has passed one million, the International Organization for Migration (IOM) says.","[('fourfold', 'ORDINAL'), ('last year', 'DATE'), ('more than 800,000', 'CARDINAL'), ('Turkey', 'GPE'), ('Greece', 'GPE'), ('Syria', 'GPE'), ('Eleven', 'CARDINAL'), ('Tuesday', 'DATE'), ('IOM', 'ORG'), ('3,695', 'CARDINAL'), ('Seven', 'CARDINAL'), ('Turkish', 'NORP'), ('Kusadasi', 'GPE'), ('Turkey', 'GPE'), ('Greek', 'NORP'), ('Syrians', 'NORP'), ('Athens', 'GPE'), ('EU', 'ORG'), ('Schengen', 'ORG'), ('Hungary', 'GPE'), ('Slovakia', 'GPE'), ('the European Court of Justice', 'ORG'), ('EU', 'ORG'), ('EU', 'ORG'), ('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Sweden', 'GPE')]",The International Organization for Migration (IOM) says the number of migrants and refugees crossing to Europe from Turkey to Greece reached 1.2 million in 2015.,"[('The International Organization for Migration', 'ORG'), ('IOM', 'ORG'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('Turkey', 'GPE'), ('Greece', 'GPE'), ('1.2 million', 'CARDINAL'), ('2015', 'DATE')]"
"The World Bank has cut its growth forecast for the Asia Pacific region for this year and next, because of the risks posed from a sharp slowdown in China and raising US interest rates.","[('East Asia', 'LOC'), ('Pacific', 'LOC'), ('6.5%', 'PERCENT'), ('this year', 'DATE'), ('6.4%', 'PERCENT'), ('2016', 'DATE'), ('6.7%', 'PERCENT'), ('6.8%', 'PERCENT'), ('last year', 'DATE'), ('Last month', 'DATE'), ('the Asian Development Bank', 'ORG'), ('China', 'GPE'), ('5.8%', 'PERCENT'), ('this year', 'DATE'), ('The International Monetary Fund', 'ORG'), ('September', 'DATE'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), (""East Asia's"", 'LOC'), ('China', 'GPE'), ('US', 'GPE'), (""the World Bank's"", 'ORG'), ('Sudhir Shetty', 'PERSON'), ('Monday', 'DATE'), ('China', 'GPE'), ('China', 'GPE'), ('East Asia', 'LOC')]","The World Bank has cut its growth forecast for the developing region, citing slowing growth in China and an expected rise in US interest rates in 2016.","[('The World Bank', 'ORG'), ('China', 'GPE'), ('US', 'GPE'), ('2016', 'DATE')]"
Wales' Bradley Dredge is pleased with his current form and hopes to build on his joint second placed finish at the Irish Open.,"[('Dredge', 'PERSON'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Russell Knox', 'PERSON'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Rory McIlroy', 'PERSON'), ('42-year-old', 'DATE'), ('the European Tour', 'EVENT'), ('66', 'CARDINAL'), ('the K Club', 'ORG'), ('Dredge', 'PERSON'), ('next week', 'DATE'), ('Dredge', 'PERSON'), ('the BMW PGA Championship', 'EVENT'), ('Wentworth', 'FAC'), ('Thursday', 'DATE'), ('26 May', 'DATE'), ('European Tour', 'ORG'), ('2013', 'DATE'), ('the European Tour', 'EVENT'), ('Dredge', 'PERSON'), ('the Irish Open', 'EVENT'), ('Dredge', 'PERSON'), ('270,000', 'MONEY'), ('the European Masters', 'EVENT'), ('2006', 'DATE'), ('Dredge', 'PERSON')]","Welshman Bradley Dredge says he is looking forward to the rest of the season after securing a £260,000 prize money at the Irish Open.","[('Bradley Dredge', 'PERSON'), ('the season', 'DATE'), ('260,000', 'MONEY'), ('the Irish Open', 'EVENT')]"
Russian-born artist Svetlana Cameron will unveil her first solo exhibition of classical portraits in the Isle of Man this week.,"[('Tony Brown', 'PERSON'), ('Cameron', 'PERSON'), ('three-week', 'DATE'), ('Sayle', 'FAC'), ('Wednesday', 'DATE'), ('Island of Culture', 'ORG'), ('Tynwald Clare', 'GPE'), ('Christian', 'NORP'), ('Nearly 30', 'CARDINAL'), ('17', 'CARDINAL'), ('Douglas', 'GPE'), ('the past four years', 'DATE'), ('Cameron', 'PERSON'), ('the Isle of Man', 'GPE'), ('Tynwald Day', 'DATE'), ('Manx', 'NORP')]",Portraits by Manx artist Sally Cameron are to go on display for the first time in the island's history at a Manx art gallery.,"[('Manx', 'NORP'), ('Sally Cameron', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Manx', 'NORP')]"
A famous art gallery has teamed up with Minecraft experts to create 3D worlds inspired by paintings.,"[('29 January 2015', 'DATE'), ('07:23 GMT', 'TIME'), ('Tate Worlds', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Tate', 'FAC'), ('Soul of the Soulless City', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Christopher Nevinson', 'PERSON'), ('1920s', 'DATE'), ('New York', 'GPE'), ('Martin', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Minecraft', 'PRODUCT')]","Paintings from the Tate gallery have been turned into Minecraft worlds for the first time in the world of the computer game, to celebrate its 50th anniversary.","[('Tate', 'PERSON'), ('Minecraft', 'FAC'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('50th', 'ORDINAL')]"
One of Donald Trump's closest advisers has told the BBC the US president-elect's criticism of German Chancellor Angela Merkel has been misinterpreted.,"[('Monday', 'DATE'), ('Trump', 'PERSON'), ('Merkel', 'PERSON'), ('Anthony Scaramucci', 'PERSON'), ('Scaramucci', 'PERSON'), ('BBC', 'ORG'), ('US', 'GPE'), ('China', 'GPE'), ('the World Economic Forum', 'ORG'), ('Davos', 'GPE'), ('Scaramucci', 'PERSON'), ('Trump', 'PERSON'), ('Merkel', 'PERSON'), ('Davos', 'GPE'), ('Scaramucci', 'PERSON'), ('the White House', 'ORG'), ('Friday', 'DATE'), ('Trump', 'PERSON'), ('European', 'NORP'), ('US', 'GPE'), ('German', 'NORP'), ('BBC', 'ORG'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('Trump', 'PERSON'), ('Times', 'ORG'), ('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Bild', 'ORG'), ('Trump', 'PERSON')]","The incoming White House communications director has defended US President-elect Donald Trump's attack on German Chancellor Angela Merkel, saying he was ""trying to be complimentary"".","[('White House', 'ORG'), ('US', 'GPE'), ('Donald Trump', 'PERSON'), ('German', 'NORP'), ('Angela Merkel', 'PERSON')]"
Badger cull protesters in Dorset say they have set up a camp for those attempting to stop marksmen killing the animals.,"[('Stop the Cull', 'ORG'), ('the Dorset Camp Badger', 'ORG'), ('Dorset Police', 'ORG'), ('Dorset', 'GPE'), ('Somerset', 'GPE'), ('Gloucestershire', 'GPE'), ('31 January', 'DATE'), ('Dorset', 'GPE'), ('six weeks', 'DATE'), ('Jared Parkin', 'PERSON'), ('Dorset Police', 'ORG'), ('Brian May', 'PERSON'), ('Save Me', 'ORG'), ('Natural England', 'ORG'), ('Gloucestershire', 'GPE'), ('Somerset', 'GPE'), ('Dorset', 'GPE'), ('Gloucestershire', 'GPE'), ('Somerset', 'GPE')]",A protest camp has been set up in Dorset ahead of the first badger cull in the UK in more than a decade. and the government has confirmed the cull is under way.,"[('Dorset', 'GPE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('UK', 'GPE'), ('more than a decade.', 'DATE')]"
Actor and comedian Eddie Murphy is to receive this year's Mark Twain Prize for American humour.,"[('First', 'ORDINAL'), ('Richard Pryor', 'PERSON'), ('1998', 'DATE'), ('19th Century', 'DATE'), ('Samuel Clemens', 'PERSON'), ('1835', 'DATE'), ('US', 'GPE'), ('Bill Cosby', 'PERSON'), ('Ellen DeGeneres', 'PERSON'), ('Jay Leno', 'PERSON'), (""last year's"", 'DATE'), ('Brooklyn', 'GPE'), ('1961', 'DATE'), ('Murphy', 'PERSON'), ('1980', 'DATE'), ('Saturday Night Live', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Beverly Hills Cop', 'ORG'), ('Coming to America', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Shrek', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Murphy', 'PERSON'), ('18 October', 'DATE'), ('the John F Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts', 'ORG'), ('Washington', 'GPE'), ('DC', 'GPE')]",Comedian and actor Eddie Murphy is to receive the Samuel Clemens Award for lifetime achievement in comedy from the US National Endowment for the Arts.,"[('Eddie Murphy', 'PERSON'), ('the Samuel Clemens Award', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('US', 'GPE'), ('National Endowment for the Arts', 'ORG')]"
A youth pastor from Sydney has created a stir online with his very simple tutorial titled How to Speak Australian.,"[('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Josh Hawkins', 'PERSON'), ('Australian', 'NORP'), ('30-year-old', 'DATE'), ('Australia', 'GPE'), ('Josh', 'PERSON'), ('Rhys Keir', 'PERSON'), ('Australia', 'GPE'), ('Facebook', 'ORG'), ('more than 1.5m', 'CARDINAL'), ('Monday', 'DATE'), ('Josh', 'PERSON'), ('May', 'DATE'), ('BBC', 'ORG'), ('Wollongong', 'GPE'), ('Sydney', 'GPE'), ('today', 'DATE'), ('Wednesday', 'DATE')]",A video by an Australian comedian has been viewed more than 1.5m times on Facebook and will be broadcast on Sydney's ABC radio on Wednesday.,"[('Australian', 'NORP'), ('more than 1.5m', 'CARDINAL'), ('Facebook', 'ORG'), ('Sydney', 'GPE'), ('ABC', 'ORG'), ('Wednesday', 'DATE')]"
Nottingham Forest defender Joe Worrall has signed a new three-and-a-half-year deal with the Championship club.,"[('Worrall', 'PERSON'), ('20', 'DATE'), ('October', 'DATE'), ('10', 'CARDINAL'), ('June 2020', 'DATE'), ('BBC Radio Nottingham', 'ORG'), ('a very proud day', 'DATE'), ('Nottingham Forest', 'ORG'), ('Reds', 'ORG'), ('Ryan Yates', 'PERSON'), ('2019', 'DATE'), ('19-year-old', 'DATE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Shrewsbury', 'ORG'), ('Barrow', 'PERSON'), ('earlier in the season', 'DATE')]",Nottingham Forest defender Liam Worrall has signed a new three-year contract with the Championship club... the club has announced.,"[('Nottingham Forest', 'ORG'), ('Liam Worrall', 'PERSON'), ('Championship', 'ORG')]"
US President Barack Obama has vowed to take action against Russia for its alleged interference in the US presidential election campaign.,"[('US', 'GPE'), ('NPR', 'ORG'), ('Russia', 'GPE'), ('US', 'GPE'), ('the Democratic Party', 'ORG'), ('Hillary Clinton', 'PERSON'), ('Kremlin', 'ORG'), ('Russian', 'NORP'), ('Vladimir Putin', 'PERSON'), ('Republican', 'NORP'), ('Donald Trump', 'PERSON'), ('Russian', 'NORP'), ('Kremlin', 'ORG'), ('Thursday', 'DATE'), ('White House', 'ORG'), ('Vladimir Putin', 'PERSON'), ('Hours later', 'TIME'), ('Obama', 'PERSON'), ('Putin', 'PERSON')]","US President Barack Obama has said the US will take action against Russia if it tries to interfere in next month's US presidential election, at its own choosing.","[('US', 'GPE'), ('Barack Obama', 'PERSON'), ('US', 'GPE'), ('Russia', 'GPE'), (""next month's"", 'DATE'), ('US', 'GPE')]"
Police officers in the US have arrested a fugitive after seeing through his elaborate disguise as an elderly man.,"[('South Yarmouth', 'GPE'), ('Massachusetts', 'GPE'), ('Shaun ""Shizz"" Miller', 'PERSON'), ('April', 'DATE'), ('South Yarmouth', 'GPE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('nearly $30,000 (Â£23,000', 'MONEY'), ('The Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco and Firearms', 'ORG'), ('Miller', 'PERSON'), ('Nauti', 'NORP'), ('twelve', 'CARDINAL')]","Police in the US have arrested a man they mistook for an ""elderly man"" after he turned out to be a drug trafficker.","[('US', 'GPE')]"
"""Sometimes our communities have not supported girls to play football, it is considered a man's game.""","[('Kenya', 'GPE'), ('Mary Kinuthia', 'PERSON'), ('2016', 'DATE'), ('Africa Women Cup of Nations', 'EVENT'), ('the Harambee Starlets', 'ORG'), ('Kinuthia', 'PERSON'), ('BBC Sport', 'ORG'), ('Kinuthia', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Kenya', 'GPE'), ('Kenya', 'GPE'), ('Cameroon', 'GPE'), ('19 November to 3 December', 'DATE'), ('Algeria', 'GPE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Kenya', 'GPE'), ('Kinuthia', 'PERSON')]","""It has not been an easy journey, but we have come a long way and we will not let anything stop us from achieving our dream.""",[]
"Astronomers have discovered the largest known solar system, consisting of a large planet that takes nearly a million years to orbit its star.","[('one trillion kilometres', 'QUANTITY'), ('140', 'CARDINAL'), ('Pluto', 'LOC'), ('Sun', 'LOC'), ('recent years', 'DATE'), ('the Royal Astronomical Society', 'ORG'), ('12', 'CARDINAL'), ('15', 'CARDINAL'), ('Jupiter', 'LOC'), ('Simon Murphy', 'PERSON'), ('the Australian National University', 'ORG'), ('ANU', 'ORG'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Earth', 'LOC'), ('Earth', 'LOC'), ('about 100 light-years', 'QUANTITY'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')]","Astronomers have discovered the largest planet ever found outside our solar system, orbiting a star about 100 light-years from Earth. and a brown dwarf.","[('about 100 light-years', 'QUANTITY')]"
Loan signing Adam Armstrong scored a brilliant debut goal to give Barnsley the points at struggling Preston.,"[('Tykes', 'NORP'), ('Armstrong', 'PERSON'), ('Newcastle', 'GPE'), ('Alex Baptiste', 'PERSON'), ('Barnsley', 'ORG'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Sam Winnall', 'PERSON'), (""Marley Watkins'"", 'PERSON'), (""Aiden McGeady's"", 'PERSON'), ('Preston', 'PERSON'), ('Lilywhites', 'NORP'), ('Championship', 'EVENT'), ('eight', 'CARDINAL'), ('last season', 'DATE'), ('Simon Grayson', 'PERSON'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('McGeady', 'PERSON'), ('Marnick Vermijl', 'PERSON'), ('Alex Baptiste', 'PERSON'), ('Barnsley', 'PERSON'), ('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('Armstrong', 'PERSON'), ('Tykes', 'NORP'), ('Adam Davies', 'PERSON'), ('Paul Gallagher', 'PERSON'), ('McGeady', 'PERSON'), ('Winnall', 'PERSON'), ('Preston', 'PERSON'), ('Jordan Hugill', 'PERSON')]",New signing Stuart Armstrong scored the only goal of the game as Barnsley beat Preston North End at Oakwell to move off the bottom of the Championship.,"[('Stuart Armstrong', 'PERSON'), ('Barnsley', 'PERSON'), ('Preston North End', 'ORG'), ('Oakwell', 'FAC'), ('Championship', 'EVENT')]"
"Lionel Ainsworth has signed a new contract with Motherwell, who say they faced competition from clubs around Britain who also wanted the winger.","[('Englishman', 'NORP'), ('season', 'DATE'), ('Fir Park', 'FAC'), ('Rotherham United', 'ORG'), ('last summer', 'DATE'), (""Ian Baraclough's"", 'PERSON'), ('SPFL Premiership', 'ORG'), ('English', 'LANGUAGE'), ('Ainsworth', 'PERSON'), ('Motherwell', 'GPE'), ('Premiership Play-off', 'EVENT'), ('Rangers', 'ORG'), ('22', 'CARDINAL'), ('two seasons', 'DATE'), ('Fir Park', 'FAC'), ('Last season', 'DATE'), ('Rangers', 'ORG'), ('Ainsworth', 'PERSON'), ('Derby County', 'GPE'), ('Watford', 'GPE'), ('Huddersfield Town', 'GPE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Marvin Johnson', 'PERSON'), ('Baraclough', 'PERSON'), ('Mar', 'PERSON')]","Motherwell winger Jonny Ainsworth has signed a new contract with the Scottish Premiership club, keeping him at Fir Park until the summer of 2018.","[('Motherwell', 'ORG'), ('Jonny Ainsworth', 'PERSON'), ('Scottish', 'NORP'), ('Fir Park', 'FAC'), ('the summer of 2018', 'DATE')]"
A grime artist from Paisley has been warned he faces jail if he continues to breach a community payback order.,"[('Joseph Heron', 'PERSON'), ('MC Shogun', 'PERSON'), (""240 hours'"", 'QUANTITY'), ('16 hours', 'TIME'), ('American', 'NORP'), ('Nas', 'PERSON'), ('the O2 Academy', 'ORG'), ('Glasgow', 'GPE'), ('last month', 'DATE'), ('James Spy', 'PERSON'), ('Heron', 'PERSON'), ('November 2015', 'DATE'), ('Paisley', 'GPE'), ('11 July', 'DATE'), ('US', 'GPE'), ('Nas', 'PERSON'), ('Michael McKeown', 'PERSON'), ('Paisley Sheriff Court', 'ORG'), ('Heron', 'PERSON'), ('2014', 'DATE')]",A Paisley rapper who failed to complete a community payback order has been warned he could be jailed if he does not comply with the order.,"[('Paisley', 'GPE')]"
Two South African men found guilty of murdering Mozambican Manuel Josias Sithole have been sentenced to 10 and 17 years.,"[('last April', 'DATE'), ('James Oatway', 'PERSON'), ('Graca Machel', 'PERSON'), ('Nelson Mandela', 'PERSON'), ('BBC', 'ORG'), ('South African', 'NORP'), ('Mozambican', 'NORP'), ('Zambian', 'NORP'), ('Zimbabwean', 'NORP'), ('Sithole', 'PERSON'), ('Mthinta Bhengu', 'PERSON'), ('Sifundo Mzimela', 'PERSON'), ('Sithole', 'PERSON'), ('Alexandra', 'GPE'), ('Johannesburg', 'GPE'), ('One', 'CARDINAL'), ('Oatway', 'PERSON'), ('Bhengu', 'PERSON'), ('17-year', 'DATE'), ('Mzimela', 'PERSON'), ('BBC', 'ORG'), ('Nomsa Maseko', 'PERSON'), ('South Africa', 'GPE'), ('Sithole', 'PERSON')]","Two South African men have been jailed for life for the murder of Mozambican man Emmanuel Sithole, who was beaten to death with a monkey wrench.","[('Two', 'CARDINAL'), ('South African', 'NORP'), ('Mozambican', 'NORP'), ('Emmanuel Sithole', 'PERSON')]"
Kevin Ellison's second-half strike sent Morecambe to the top of the early League Two table as they claimed victory at Yeovil Town.,"[('37-year-old', 'DATE'), ('Shrimps', 'PERSON'), ('the 55th minute', 'TIME'), ('Jack Dunn', 'PERSON'), ('Lee Molyneux', 'PERSON'), ('Ellison', 'PERSON'), ('Glovers', 'PERSON'), ('Artur Krysiak', 'PERSON'), ('Morecambe', 'PERSON'), ('Barry Roche', 'PERSON'), ('Tom Eaves', 'PERSON'), ('Matty Dolan', 'PERSON'), ('Roche', 'PERSON'), ('Tahvon Campbell', 'PERSON'), ('Dolan', 'PERSON'), ('25 yards', 'QUANTITY'), ('Ellison', 'PERSON'), ('the 62nd minute', 'TIME'), ('Krysiak', 'PERSON'), ('Molyneux', 'PERSON'), ('Press Association', 'ORG'), ('Yeovil Town 0', 'FAC'), ('Morecambe', 'GPE'), ('1', 'CARDINAL'), ('Second Half', 'TIME'), ('Yeovil Town 0', 'FAC'), ('Morecambe', 'GPE'), ('1', 'CARDINAL'), ('Yeovil Town', 'GPE'), ('Barry Roche', 'PERSON'), ('Matthew Dolan', 'PERSON')]",Morecambe moved into the League Two play-off places with a 1-0 win at Yeovil thanks to Craig Ellison's goal.,"[('Morecambe', 'PERSON'), ('Two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Yeovil', 'GPE'), (""Craig Ellison's"", 'PERSON')]"
Police in Bangladesh say they have shot dead the main suspect in the killing of secularist blogger Avijit Roy.,"[('Sharif', 'PERSON'), ('Dhaka', 'GPE'), ('Sunday', 'DATE'), ('Sharif', 'PERSON'), ('six', 'CARDINAL'), ('Avijit Roy', 'PERSON'), ('American-Bangladeshi', 'NORP'), ('Dhaka', 'GPE'), ('February last year', 'DATE'), ('Bangladesh', 'GPE'), ('Bangladesh', 'GPE'), ('Bangladesh', 'GPE'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Islamists', 'NORP'), ('recent years', 'DATE'), ('Bangladesh', 'GPE'), ('Islamic State', 'ORG'), ('al-Qaeda', 'ORG'), ('Roy', 'PERSON'), ('42', 'DATE'), ('the Mukto-Mona (""Free Mind', 'ORG'), ('2000', 'DATE'), ('Bangladesh', 'GPE'), ('Islamist', 'NORP')]",Bangladeshi police say they have killed a man suspected of being involved in the murder of secularist blogger Avijit Roy last year.,"[('Bangladeshi', 'NORP'), ('Avijit Roy', 'PERSON'), ('last year', 'DATE')]"
Malaysia says it is sending a team of experts to the Maldives to investigate reports that debris from the missing Flight MH370 has washed up there.,"[('Maldives', 'GPE'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Malaysian', 'NORP'), ('Liow Tiong Lai', 'PERSON'), ('MH370', 'PRODUCT'), ('Malaysia Airlines', 'ORG'), ('239', 'CARDINAL'), ('Kuala Lumpur', 'GPE'), ('Beijing', 'GPE'), ('March 2014', 'DATE'), ('Indian Ocean', 'LOC'), ('Maldives', 'GPE'), ('just days', 'DATE'), ('French', 'NORP'), ('Indian Ocean', 'LOC'), ('Reunion', 'LOC'), ('Maldives', 'GPE'), ('Liow', 'PERSON'), ('Monday', 'DATE'), ('Haveeru', 'GPE')]",Malaysia says it will send a team to the Maldives to investigate reports that debris has been found there from the missing flight MH370.,"[('Malaysia', 'GPE'), ('Maldives', 'GPE'), ('MH370', 'PRODUCT')]"
"In one of his last official functions as Taoiseach, Enda Kenny has joined Prince William, the Duke of Cambridge, at Messines in northern France to commemorate the centenary of the battle there.","[('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('36th', 'ORDINAL'), ('Ulster', 'GPE'), ('16th', 'ORDINAL'), ('Irish Divisions', 'ORG'), ('World War One', 'EVENT'), ('Collins Barracks', 'FAC'), ('Dublin', 'GPE'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('30,000', 'CARDINAL'), ('Triumph H', 'PRODUCT'), ('World War One', 'EVENT'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Patrick Hunt', 'PERSON'), ('Dublin', 'GPE'), ('the Boer War', 'EVENT'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Kevin Myers', 'PERSON'), ('London', 'GPE'), ('Fr Willie Doyle', 'PERSON'), ('Jesuit', 'NORP'), ('Messines', 'ORG'), ('Messines', 'EVENT')]","The centenary of the Battle of Messines is being marked in the Republic of Ireland this week... Xie, a member of the 36th Ulster and 16th Irish Divisions, is among those commemorating the event.","[('the Battle of Messines', 'EVENT'), ('the Republic of Ireland', 'GPE'), ('Xie', 'PERSON'), ('36th', 'ORDINAL'), ('Ulster', 'ORG'), ('16th', 'ORDINAL'), ('Irish Divisions', 'ORG')]"
Reading defender Chris Gunter believes Jaap Stam's consistent approach in management has helped to maintain their Championship play-off push.,"[('the day', 'DATE'), ('7-1', 'CARDINAL'), ('Norwich', 'ORG'), ('Aston Villa', 'LOC'), ('Wales', 'GPE'), ('Reading', 'PERSON'), ('Gunter', 'PERSON'), ('Nottingham Forest', 'FAC'), ('Saturday', 'DATE'), ('Paul McShane', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Forest', 'ORG'), ('Gunter', 'PERSON'), ('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('five-nil', 'CARDINAL')]","Reading defender Chris Gunter says his team-mate Gary McAllister is a ""great leader"" and has not changed his approach since taking the armband.","[('Chris Gunter', 'PERSON'), ('Gary McAllister', 'PERSON')]"
"Bad luck caused by disturbed fairy forts is causing dips in a major road between County Kerry and County Cork, an Irish member of parliament has said.","[('Danny Healy-Rae', 'PERSON'), ('the Irish Times', 'ORG'), ('N22', 'EVENT'), ('Healy-Rae', 'PERSON'), ('N22', 'FAC'), ('Killarney', 'GPE'), ('County Kerry', 'GPE'), ('Cork', 'GPE'), ('Irish', 'NORP'), ('Healy-Rae', 'PERSON'), ('TD', 'ORG'), ('Irish', 'NORP'), ('County Kerry', 'PERSON')]","An Irish politician has said he has a machine standing in his yard to repair a road in County Kerry that has been damaged by ""fairy forts"".","[('Irish', 'NORP'), ('County Kerry', 'GPE')]"
"In our series of letters from African journalists, social commentator Joseph Warungu asks why Kenya's governing coalition has launched its new Jubilee Party.","[('about six years', 'DATE'), ('Kenya', 'GPE'), ('Uhuru Kenyatta', 'PERSON'), ('William Ruto', 'PERSON'), ('Saturday', 'DATE'), ('12kg', 'CARDINAL'), ('Jubilee', 'ORG'), ('Kenyatta', 'PERSON'), ('Kikuyu', 'NORP'), ('five', 'CARDINAL'), ('Kenya', 'GPE'), ('thousands', 'CARDINAL'), ('Ruto', 'PERSON'), ('Kalenjin', 'NORP'), ('Jubilee', 'ORG'), ('the millions of shillings', 'MONEY')]","In our series of letters from African journalists, film-maker and columnist Farai Sevenzo looks at the birth of a baby boy in Kenya.","[('African', 'NORP'), ('Farai Sevenzo', 'PERSON'), ('Kenya', 'GPE')]"
A PSNI officer has told a court that a County Tyrone father and son accused of drugs offences are believed to be senior members of a mid-Ulster organised crime gang.,"[('Paul Joseph Currie', 'PERSON'), ('53', 'DATE'), ('Limekiln Lane', 'GPE'), ('Stephen Currie', 'PERSON'), ('29', 'DATE'), ('Coolnafranky Park', 'GPE'), ('Cookstown', 'GPE'), ('Dungannon Magistrates Court', 'FAC'), ('earlier this month', 'DATE'), ('1.5m', 'MONEY'), ('Wednesday', 'DATE'), ('Darren Loughlin', 'PERSON'), ('Gortacar Road', 'FAC'), ('Kesh', 'GPE'), ('County Fermanagh', 'GPE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')]",A father and son from County Tyrone have been remanded in custody charged in connection with a £1.5m drugs haul in County Fermanagh.,"[('County Tyrone', 'GPE'), ('1.5m', 'MONEY'), ('County Fermanagh', 'GPE')]"
A look at the best actor nominees for the 87th Academy Awards.,"[('33', 'CARDINAL'), ('Stephen Hawking', 'PERSON'), ('A Brief History of Time', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Oscar', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Oscar', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Redmayne', 'PERSON'), ('Daniel Day-Lewis', 'PERSON'), ('My Left Foot', 'ORG'), ('Hawking', 'PERSON'), ('two hours', 'TIME'), ('Catherine Shoard', 'PERSON'), ('The Guardian', 'ORG'), ('52', 'CARDINAL'), ('Foxcatcher', 'ORG'), ('Carell', 'PERSON'), ('John du Pont', 'PERSON'), ('Olympic', 'EVENT'), ('Oscar', 'PERSON'), ('Carell', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Carell', 'PERSON')]","Eddie Redmayne and Steve Carell are among the nominees for the 88th Academy Awards, which will be held in Los Angeles on 26 February 2017.","[('Eddie Redmayne', 'PERSON'), ('Steve Carell', 'PERSON'), ('88th', 'ORDINAL'), ('Academy Awards', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Los Angeles', 'GPE'), ('26 February 2017', 'DATE')]"
"Protests over youth unemployment have spread to several towns and cities in Tunisia, leading to the death of a policeman in clashes on Thursday.","[('Kasserine', 'LOC'), ('Feriana', 'GPE'), ('2011', 'DATE'), ('Zine al-Abidine Ben Ali', 'PERSON'), ('Mohamed Bouazizi', 'PERSON'), ('Sidi Bouzid', 'GPE'), ('this week', 'DATE'), ('2011', 'DATE'), ('More than a third', 'CARDINAL'), ('62%', 'PERCENT'), ('Tunisian', 'NORP'), ('OECD', 'ORG'), ('five years', 'DATE'), ('Yassine Kahlaoui', 'PERSON'), ('30-year-old', 'DATE'), ('the Associated Press', 'ORG'), ('Kasserine', 'GPE'), ('Tunisia', 'GPE'), ('Beji Caid Essebsi', 'PERSON'), ('Wednesday', 'DATE')]",Tunisian police have fired tear gas and used water cannon to disperse thousands of people protesting against high levels of unemployment and unemployment-related deaths.,"[('Tunisian', 'NORP'), ('thousands', 'CARDINAL')]"
Former Nigeria captain Jay-Jay Okocha urged the country's football authority to swiftly resolve the national team's managerial vacancy in order to prevent further setbacks.,"[('Daniel Amokachi', 'PERSON'), ('Nigeria', 'GPE'), ('December', 'DATE'), ('Stephen Keshi', 'PERSON'), ('the Nigeria Football Federation', 'ORG'), ('NFF', 'ORG'), ('NFF', 'ORG'), ('Amaju Pinnick', 'PERSON'), ('two weeks ago', 'DATE'), ('Keshi', 'PERSON'), ('the Nations Cup', 'EVENT'), ('Okocha', 'PERSON'), ('the Nations Cup', 'EVENT'), ('1994', 'DATE'), ('1996', 'DATE'), ('Olympics', 'EVENT'), ('Atlanta', 'GPE'), ('2017', 'DATE'), ('Africa Cup of Nations', 'EVENT'), ('Gabon', 'GPE'), ('the Nations Cup', 'EVENT'), ('Okocha', 'PERSON'), ('BBC Sport', 'ORG'), ('Nigerians', 'NORP')]","Nigeria need to resolve their coaching crisis quickly to prevent another troubled qualifying race for the 2017 Africa Cup of Nations, says former national team captain Victor Okocha.","[('Nigeria', 'GPE'), ('the 2017 Africa Cup of Nations', 'EVENT'), ('Victor Okocha', 'PERSON')]"
Opponents of an overhead cables scheme across parts of rural Denbighshire and Conwy have won the right to a judicial review.,"[('July', 'DATE'), ('UK Energy', 'ORG'), ('Greg Clark', 'PERSON'), (""SP Manweb's"", 'ORG'), ('17km (10.5 miles)', 'QUANTITY'), ('Clocaenog', 'GPE'), ('Glascoed', 'GPE'), ('last year', 'DATE'), ('SP Manweb', 'ORG'), ('High Court', 'ORG'), ('Llangefni', 'GPE'), ('April', 'DATE'), ('The Pylon the Pressure', 'ORG'), ('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('Clocaenog', 'GPE'), ('Brenig', 'GPE'), ('Dyfrig Hughes', 'PERSON'), ('Wales', 'GPE'), ('UK', 'GPE'), ('SP', 'ORG'), ('Manweb', 'ORG'), ('UK Energy', 'ORG'), ('Ed Davey', 'PERSON'), ('Â£16m', 'MONEY')]","Plans to lay underground power lines in Gwynedd are to be reviewed by the High Court, campaigners have said, despite the scheme being approved by the UK government.","[('Gwynedd', 'GPE'), ('the High Court', 'ORG'), ('UK', 'GPE')]"
Thousands of customers with funds in the UK arm of Cypriot bank Laiki will escape any levy on their accounts.,"[(""The Bank of England's"", 'ORG'), ('Prudential Regulation Authority', 'ORG'), ('PRA', 'ORG'), ('Bank of Cyprus', 'ORG'), ('UK', 'GPE'), ('up to £85,000', 'MONEY'), ('UK', 'GPE'), ('Laiki', 'NORP'), ('Cyprus', 'GPE'), ('the European Union', 'ORG'), ('more than 100,000 euros', 'MONEY'), ('up to 60%', 'PERCENT'), ('15,000', 'CARDINAL'), ('Laiki', 'ORG'), ('an estimated £270m', 'MONEY'), ('UK', 'GPE'), ('Bank of Cyprus UK', 'ORG'), ('UK', 'GPE'), ('Laiki Bank', 'ORG'), ('Bank of Cyprus UK', 'ORG'), ('UK', 'GPE'), ('PRA', 'ORG'), ('Laiki', 'ORG'), ('UK', 'GPE'), ('18,000', 'MONEY'), ('About 5%', 'PERCENT'), ('more than £85,000', 'MONEY'), ('Bank of Cyprus UK', 'ORG')]",Thousands of Laiki Bank customers in the UK are being told their money will be protected under the UK compensation scheme for the bank's collapse in Cyprus.,"[('Thousands', 'CARDINAL'), ('Laiki Bank', 'ORG'), ('UK', 'GPE'), ('UK', 'GPE'), ('Cyprus', 'GPE')]"
"The US military says it is sending 1,000 anti-tank missiles to the Iraqi government following the fall of Ramadi to Islamic State (IS) forces.","[('Baghdad', 'GPE'), ('Iraqi', 'NORP'), ('Col Pat Ryder', 'PERSON'), ('More than 40,000', 'CARDINAL'), ('Ramadi', 'GPE'), ('last Friday', 'DATE'), ('Wednesday', 'DATE'), ('thousands', 'CARDINAL'), ('Anbar', 'GPE'), ('Baghdad', 'GPE'), ('several days', 'DATE'), ('Ramadi', 'GPE'), ('Associated Press', 'ORG'), ('Anbar', 'GPE'), ('at least 500', 'CARDINAL'), ('three days', 'DATE'), ('Ramadi', 'GPE'), ('last week', 'DATE'), ('Col Ryder', 'PERSON')]","Iraqi forces have begun deploying surface-to-air missiles in the city of Ramadi, which was seized by so-called Islamic State (IS) last week.","[('Iraqi', 'NORP'), ('Ramadi', 'GPE'), ('Islamic State (IS', 'ORG'), ('last week', 'DATE')]"
League Two side Northampton Town have signed Sheffield United striker Dominic Calvert-Lewin on loan until January.,"[('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Blades', 'PERSON'), ('Stalybridge Celtic', 'ORG'), ('six', 'CARDINAL'), ('Calvert-Lewin', 'ORG'), ('Ivan Toney', 'PERSON'), ('Newcastle', 'GPE'), ('Cobbler', 'PERSON'), ('Chris Wilder', 'PERSON')]","League One side Rochdale have signed Sheffield United winger Dominic Calvert-Lewin on loan until the end of the season, with a view to a permanent move.","[('League One', 'ORG'), ('Rochdale', 'ORG'), ('Sheffield United', 'ORG'), ('Dominic Calvert-Lewin', 'PERSON'), ('the end of the season', 'DATE')]"
World number one Novak Djokovic complained to the umpire that he could smell cannabis on court during his Rogers Cup win over Jeremy Chardy.,"[('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Serb', 'NORP'), ('Djokovic', 'PERSON'), ('tomorrow', 'DATE'), ('seventh', 'ORDINAL'), ('Djokovic', 'PERSON'), ('Janko Tipsarevic', 'PERSON'), ('Friday', 'DATE'), ('Yesterday', 'DATE'), ('today', 'DATE'), ('Djokovic', 'PERSON'), ('Frenchman', 'NORP'), ('Britain', 'GPE'), ('Andy Murray', 'PERSON'), ('Sunday', 'DATE')]",World number one Novak Djokovic said he thought someone was smoking marijuana during his win over Lucas Pouille in the French Open semi-finals.,"[('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Novak Djokovic', 'PERSON'), ('Lucas Pouille', 'PERSON'), ('the French Open', 'EVENT')]"
Airbus has won a patent for a hypersonic passenger plane which could potentially fly from London to New York in an hour.,"[('Concord 2.0', 'PRODUCT'), ('more than four', 'CARDINAL'), ('the US Patent Office', 'ORG'), ('4.5', 'CARDINAL'), ('four-and-a-half', 'CARDINAL'), ('2', 'CARDINAL'), ('Concorde', 'ORG'), ('Two', 'CARDINAL'), ('a Space Shuttle', 'PRODUCT'), ('more than 100,000 feet', 'QUANTITY'), ('4.5', 'CARDINAL'), ('PatentYogi', 'ORG')]","Patent applications have been lodged in the US for an aeroplane that would rival Concorde in its speed and power source, according to US media reports.","[('US', 'GPE'), ('Concorde', 'ORG'), ('US', 'GPE')]"
Rangers striker Martyn Waghorn insists he will happily sacrifice an extended summer break if it means getting a taste of European action.,"[('Pedro Caixinha', 'PERSON'), ('Thursday', 'DATE'), ('pre-season', 'DATE'), ('Waghorn', 'PERSON'), ('Europa League', 'ORG'), ('European', 'NORP'), ('10 days', 'DATE'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Rangers', 'NORP'), ('European', 'NORP'), ('Waghorn', 'PERSON'), ('Rangers', 'ORG'), ('Celtic', 'ORG'), ('Glasgow', 'GPE'), ('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('five', 'CARDINAL'), ('Rangers', 'ORG'), ('Celtic', 'ORG'), ('Sun', 'GPE')]",Rangers midfielder Martyn Waghorn insists there is no rift in the squad ahead of next month's pre-season tour of the United States.,"[('Rangers', 'ORG'), ('Martyn Waghorn', 'PERSON'), (""next month's"", 'DATE'), ('the United States', 'GPE')]"
Head coach Jason Strange says Wales Under-20 can take positives from the 34-22 defeat by England in World Rugby's Junior Championship.,"[('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Tbilisi', 'GPE'), ('Georgia', 'GPE'), ('Australia', 'GPE'), ('Australia', 'GPE'), ('Wales', 'GPE'), ('Samoa', 'GPE'), ('Pool A', 'EVENT')]",Wales head coach Warren Gatland says his side will take positives from their 24-10 defeat by Georgia in the Rugby World Cup on Saturday.,"[('Wales', 'GPE'), ('Warren Gatland', 'PERSON'), ('24-10', 'ORG'), ('Georgia', 'GPE'), ('the Rugby World Cup', 'EVENT'), ('Saturday', 'DATE')]"
A 70-year-old man has been found guilty of murdering a fellow pensioner in the Borders.,"[('Richard Cassidy', 'PERSON'), ('David Farish', 'PERSON'), ('14', 'CARDINAL'), ('Tweedbank', 'GPE'), ('Cassidy', 'PERSON'), ('the High Court', 'ORG'), ('Glasgow', 'GPE'), ('Farish', 'PERSON'), ('February last year', 'DATE'), ('Cassidy', 'PERSON'), ('next month', 'DATE'), ('Farish', 'PERSON'), ('Cassidy', 'PERSON'), ('seven', 'DATE'), ('Farish', 'PERSON')]",A 72-year-old former soldier has been found guilty of murdering a pensioner in Fife after he confronted him about allegations of sexual abuse.,"[('72-year-old', 'DATE'), ('Fife', 'GPE')]"
Walsall piled the misery on managerless Shrewsbury as Erhun Oztumer's late winner settled a bad-tempered game in the Saddlers' favour.,"[('the 23rd minute', 'TIME'), ('Amadou Bakayoko', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Jayson Leutwiler', 'PERSON'), ('Oztumer', 'PERSON'), ('Shrewsbury', 'GPE'), ('the half hour', 'TIME'), ('Walsall', 'ORG'), ('Oliver Lancashire', 'PERSON'), (""Ian Black's"", 'PERSON'), ('Saddlers', 'ORG'), ('three minutes before half-time', 'TIME'), ('Kieron Morris', 'PERSON'), (""Joe Edwards'"", 'PERSON'), ('Oztumer', 'PERSON'), ('10 minutes into the second half', 'TIME'), ('Leutwiler', 'PERSON'), ('Shrews', 'PERSON'), ('the 58th minute', 'TIME'), ('Walsall', 'PERSON'), ('Neil Etheridge', 'PERSON'), ('Junior Brown', 'PERSON'), ('Shrewsbury', 'ORG'), ('Andy Mangan', 'PERSON'), ('George Waring', 'PERSON'), (""James O'Connor"", 'PERSON'), ('10', 'CARDINAL'), ('65 minutes', 'TIME'), ('Ryan McGivern', 'PERSON'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Bakayoko', 'PERSON'), ('Wal', 'ORG')]",Shrewsbury missed the chance to move into the League One play-off places as they were held to a draw by Walsall.,"[('Shrewsbury', 'ORG'), ('League One', 'ORG'), ('Walsall', 'ORG')]"
League Two side Colchester United have signed former Gillingham captain Doug Loft on a two-year deal.,"[('29-year-old', 'DATE'), ('Port Vale', 'GPE'), ('2014', 'DATE'), ('six', 'CARDINAL'), ('70', 'CARDINAL'), ('Gills', 'PERSON'), ('Loft', 'PERSON'), ('League Two', 'ORG'), ('2013', 'DATE'), ('Vale', 'PERSON'), ('Gills', 'PERSON'), ('the end of the season', 'DATE'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('ex-Gillingham', 'NORP'), (""the U's"", 'ORG'), ('this summer', 'DATE'), ('Brennan Dickenson', 'PERSON')]","League Two side Cambridge United have signed former Gillingham captain Chris Loft on a two-year deal, with the option of a further 12 months.","[('League Two', 'ORG'), ('Cambridge United', 'ORG'), ('Gillingham', 'ORG'), ('Chris Loft', 'PERSON'), ('a further 12 months', 'DATE')]"
"A big explosion in the Turkish city of Diyarbakir which originally appeared to be an accident was actually the result of a terror attack, the interior minister has said.","[('Suleyman Soylu', 'PERSON'), ('Turkish', 'NORP'), ('Three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Tuesday', 'DATE'), ('Kurdish', 'NORP'), (""the Kurdistan Workers' Party"", 'ORG'), ('PKK', 'ORG'), ('PKK', 'ORG'), ('Kurds', 'NORP'), ('Diyarbakir', 'GPE'), ('Tuesday', 'DATE'), ('four days', 'DATE'), ('Recep Tayyip Erdogan', 'PERSON'), ('Turkey', 'GPE'), ('Soylu', 'PERSON'), ('Haberturk', 'ORG')]","The deadly explosion in the Turkish city of Diyarbakir was the result of a ""terrorist attack"", the interior minister has said..","[('Turkish', 'NORP'), ('Diyarbakir', 'GPE')]"
James Norwood's first-half brace was enough to give Tranmere a 2-0 win at Bromley to start their 2016-17 National League campaign in style.,"[('25-year-old', 'DATE'), ('19', 'CARDINAL'), ('Prenton Park', 'FAC'), ('last year', 'DATE'), ('Rovers', 'PERSON'), ('nine minutes', 'TIME'), ('Alan Julian', 'PERSON'), (""Connor Jennings'"", 'PERSON'), ('Blair Turgott', 'PERSON'), ('six yards', 'QUANTITY'), ('40 minutes', 'TIME'), ('Tobi Sho-Silva', 'PERSON'), ('Tranmere', 'PERSON'), ('West Ham', 'LOC'), ('Four minutes', 'TIME'), ('Norwood', 'PERSON'), ('2-0', 'TIME'), (""Andy Cook's"", 'PERSON'), (""Liam Ridehalgh's"", 'PERSON'), ('Merseysiders', 'NORP'), ('the Press Association', 'ORG'), ('Tranmere Rovers', 'PERSON'), ('2', 'CARDINAL'), ('Second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Bromley 0', 'FAC'), ('Tranmere Rovers', 'PERSON'), ('2', 'CARDINAL'), ('Tranmere Rovers', 'PERSON'), ('Jake Kirby', 'PERSON'), ('James Norwood', 'PERSON'), ('Tranmere Rovers', 'GPE'), ('Bromley', 'PERSON'), ('Rob Swaine', 'PERSON'), ('Joe Howe', 'PERSON'), ('Tranmere Rovers', 'PERSON'), ('Adam Mekki', 'PERSON'), ('Andy Cook', 'PERSON'), ('Bromley', 'PERSON'), ('George Porter', 'PERSON'), ('Reece Prestedge', 'PERSON'), ('Connor', 'PERSON')]",James Norwood scored twice as Tranmere made a winning start to the National League season with a 2-0 victory at Bromley..,"[('James Norwood', 'PERSON'), ('Tranmere', 'PERSON'), ('National League', 'ORG'), ('2-0', 'CARDINAL'), ('Bromley.', 'GPE')]"
"UK charities in receipt of EU funds should not campaign for a vote to stay in the EU solely because of potential losses in income, new guidance says.","[('The Charity Commission', 'ORG'), ('EU', 'ORG'), ('Britain', 'GPE'), ('EU', 'ORG'), ('23 June', 'DATE'), ('EU', 'ORG'), ('UK', 'GPE'), ('EU', 'ORG'), ('EU', 'ORG')]","Charities in direct receipt of EU funding should not campaign for the UK to remain in the EU, new guidance has said, despite the possibility of losing their funding.","[('EU', 'ORG'), ('UK', 'GPE'), ('EU', 'ORG')]"
Five restaurants in Scotland have achieved a Top 50 listing in the 2017 Good Food Guide (GFG).,"[('Scottish', 'NORP'), ('Restaurant Andrew Fairlie', 'ORG'), ('Gleneagles', 'ORG'), ('French', 'NORP'), ('Glasgow', 'GPE'), ('GFG', 'ORG'), ('Waitrose', 'ORG'), ('Britain', 'GPE'), ('Andrew Fairlie', 'PERSON'), ('nine', 'CARDINAL'), ('UK', 'GPE'), ('GFG', 'ORG'), ('Elizabeth Carter', 'PERSON'), ('Fairlie', 'PERSON'), ('Gartmorn Farm', 'FAC'), ('French', 'NORP'), ('Scottish', 'NORP'), ('The Peat Inn', 'ORG'), ('Fife', 'GPE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Leith - The Kitchin', 'FAC')]",Glasgow has been named as the best city in the UK for restaurants in a new guide by The Great British Food Guide (GFG).,"[('Glasgow', 'GPE'), ('UK', 'GPE'), ('The Great British Food Guide', 'ORG'), ('GFG', 'ORG')]"
"More than 80 new jobs will be created in Londonderry by the insurance company, Axa.","[('Springtown', 'GPE'), ('300', 'CARDINAL'), ('Axa', 'ORG'), ('2007', 'DATE'), ('February', 'DATE'), ('Dublin', 'GPE'), ('Sean Harnett', 'PERSON'), ('Derry', 'GPE'), ('Island', 'LOC'), ('Ireland', 'LOC'), ('AXA', 'ORG'), ('15', 'CARDINAL'), ('Northern Ireland', 'GPE')]","Axa, the insurance company, is to create 50 new jobs in Londonderry over the next two years, the company has announced.","[('Axa', 'ORG'), ('50', 'CARDINAL'), ('Londonderry', 'GPE'), ('the next two years', 'DATE')]"
"The European Tour have thrown everything at bolstering this week's centenary French Open but with only partial success which, along with the latest Olympic withdrawals, serves to highlight the selfish nature of professional golfers.","[('Ryder Cup', 'EVENT'), ('Paris', 'GPE'), ('French', 'NORP'), ('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('Rory McIlroy', 'PERSON'), ('Danny Willett', 'PERSON'), ('Sergio Garcia', 'PERSON'), ('Justin Rose', 'PERSON'), (""last week's"", 'DATE'), ('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Henrik Stenson', 'PERSON'), ('Tour', 'ORG'), ('Keith Pelley', 'PERSON'), ('Ryder Cup', 'EVENT'), ('Le Golf National', 'FAC'), ('European', 'NORP'), ('Hazeltine', 'ORG'), ('this September', 'DATE'), ('64', 'CARDINAL'), ('a million', 'CARDINAL'), ('European', 'NORP'), ('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('European', 'NORP'), ('five', 'CARDINAL'), ('nine', 'CARDINAL')]",The European Tour should be ashamed of itself for failing to persuade some of the world's top players to play in the French Open this week..,"[('The European Tour', 'ORG'), ('the French Open', 'EVENT'), ('this week.', 'DATE')]"
"Three men, thought to be Iranian nationals, have been rescued from a sinking vessel off the Sussex coast.","[('Dover', 'GPE'), ('about 09:30 BST', 'TIME'), ('Hastings', 'GPE'), ('Hastings', 'ORG'), ('Kent-based', 'ORG'), ('Border Force', 'ORG'), ('Home Office', 'ORG'), ('the Border Force', 'ORG'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('HMC Seeker', 'ORG'), ('Iranian', 'NORP'), ('The Maritime and Coastguard Agency (MCA)', 'ORG'), ('Kent', 'GPE'), ('Sussex', 'GPE'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('MCA', 'ORG'), ('UK Border Force', 'ORG')]","Three men believed to be Iranian nationals have been rescued from a dinghy off the Kent/Sussex coast, the Home Office has told the BBC.","[('Three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Iranian', 'NORP'), ('Kent', 'GPE'), ('Sussex', 'GPE'), ('the Home Office', 'ORG'), ('BBC', 'ORG')]"
"This summer, BBC Sport has again broadcast live commentary on every day's play of every match in the county season.","[('summer', 'DATE'), ('Yorkshire', 'GPE'), ('the County Championship', 'EVENT'), ('Lancashire', 'GPE'), ('T20 Blast', 'EVENT'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Gloucestershire', 'GPE'), ('just over a decade ago', 'DATE'), ('One-Day Cup', 'EVENT'), ('BBC', 'ORG'), ('2015', 'DATE'), ('Season', 'DATE'), ('Kent', 'ORG'), ('Sam Northeast', 'PERSON'), ('Warwickshire', 'GPE'), ('Rikki Clarke', 'PERSON'), ('Jeetan Patel', 'PERSON'), ('Derbyshire', 'GPE'), ('Mark Footitt', 'PERSON'), ('Team of the Season', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Twitter', 'ORG'), (""Alex Hales'"", 'PERSON'), ('2015', 'DATE'), ('Three', 'CARDINAL'), ('180', 'CARDINAL'), ('236', 'CARDINAL'), ('Yorkshire', 'GPE'), ('1,000', 'CARDINAL'), ('the second season in a row', 'DATE')]","It has been an eventful year for county cricket in England and Wales, and we want to celebrate that with our 2015 Team of the Season.","[('an eventful year', 'DATE'), ('England', 'GPE'), ('Wales', 'GPE'), ('2015', 'DATE')]"
Hereford United has promised a new investor will be brought in before the next court hearing into unpaid debts.,"[('Herefordshire Council', 'ORG'), ('Friday', 'DATE'), ('six weeks', 'DATE'), ('Monday', 'DATE'), ('Andy Lonsdale', 'PERSON'), ('three weeks', 'DATE'), ('Â£500,000 to Â£600,000', 'MONEY'), ('Hereford United', 'ORG'), ('two to three weeks', 'DATE'), ('Herefordshire Council', 'ORG'), ('Edgar Street', 'FAC'), ('Thursday', 'DATE'), ('evening', 'TIME'), ('Monday', 'DATE'), ('seventh', 'ORDINAL'), ('HM Revenue and Customs', 'ORG'), ('September', 'DATE')]","Hereford United has said it has found a new investor and sponsor as it attempts to avoid being wound up by the High Court, its chairman has said.","[('Hereford United', 'ORG'), ('the High Court', 'ORG')]"
"France's audit body, the Cour des Comptes, has accused Paris Opera directors of misusing public funds on taxis, restaurants and food.","[('2013', 'DATE'), ('2014', 'DATE'), ('about 10', 'CARDINAL'), ('close to €100,000 (£85,000', 'MONEY'), ('112,000', 'MONEY'), ('Opera', 'ORG'), ('Paris', 'GPE'), ('the Paris Opera', 'FAC'), ('French', 'NORP'), ('French', 'NORP'), ('Benjamin Millepied', 'PERSON'), ('Millepied', 'PERSON'), ('Hollywood', 'GPE'), ('Nathalie Portman', 'PERSON'), ('Paris Opera', 'ORG'), ('Le Parisien', 'ORG'), ('Jean-Philippe Thiellay', 'PERSON'), ('August 2014', 'DATE')]","The Paris Opera has been criticised by auditors for spending too much money on taxis and chauffeurs, in a report seen by the BBC.","[('The Paris Opera', 'ORG'), ('BBC', 'ORG')]"
"Rangers marked Pedro Caixinha's first match as manager with a comfortable Scottish Premiership win over Hamilton Academical, who slipped to bottom.","[('Emerson Hyndman', 'PERSON'), (""James Tavernier's"", 'PERSON'), ('Clint Hill', 'PERSON'), (""Jon Toral's"", 'PERSON'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Martyn Waghorn', 'PERSON'), ('Hamilton', 'PERSON'), ('Massimo Donati', 'PERSON'), ('Ibrox', 'ORG'), (""Lee Wallace's"", 'PERSON'), ('Ibrox', 'ORG'), ('eight', 'CARDINAL'), ('Aberdeen', 'GPE'), ('seven', 'CARDINAL'), ('St Johnstone', 'PERSON'), ('third', 'ORDINAL'), ('Europa League', 'ORG'), ('Inverness Caledonian Thistle', 'ORG'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Motherwell', 'ORG'), ('Caixinha', 'PERSON'), ('46', 'DATE'), ('Mark Warburton', 'PERSON'), ('earlier this month', 'DATE'), ('Sunday', 'DATE'), ('1-1', 'ORDINAL'), ('Celtic', 'ORG'), ('Graeme Murty', 'PERSON'), ('Portuguese', 'NORP'), ('Toral', 'PERSON'), ('Lee Hodson', 'PERSON'), ('Hamilton', 'ORG'), ('Martin Canning', 'PERSON'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), (""last week's"", 'DATE'), ('Hearts', 'PERSON')]",New Rangers manager Pedro Caixinha won his first game in charge as his side beat Hamilton Academical to move up to third in the Premiership.,"[('New Rangers', 'ORG'), ('Pedro Caixinha', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Hamilton Academical', 'ORG'), ('third', 'ORDINAL'), ('Premiership', 'ORG')]"
Two men have been arrested on suspicion of murder after the body of a man was found at a flat in Southampton.,"[('Westridge Road', 'FAC'), ('St Denys', 'GPE'), ('Friday', 'DATE'), ('afternoon', 'TIME'), ('Hampshire Constabulary', 'ORG'), ('26-year old', 'DATE'), ('35-year-old', 'CARDINAL'), ('Southampton', 'GPE'), ('Nick Heelan', 'PERSON')]","Two men have been arrested on suspicion of murder after the body of a man was found at a house in Southampton in what police described as an ""isolated incident"".","[('Two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Southampton', 'GPE')]"
"Tesla will update its cars' Autopilot function with new safety features designed to prevent collisions, the company has announced.","[('Elon Musk', 'PERSON'), ('Sunday', 'DATE'), ('Tesla', 'ORG'), ('earlier this year', 'DATE'), ('Autopilot', 'PRODUCT'), ('200-plus', 'CARDINAL'), ('US', 'GPE'), ('Tesla', 'ORG'), ('May', 'DATE'), ('the US National Highway Traffic Safety Administration', 'ORG'), ('BBC', 'ORG')]","Tesla is updating the software on its Autopilot system in an attempt to make it safer for drivers and more accurate at spotting obstacles ahead, the company has said.","[('Tesla', 'ORG'), ('Autopilot', 'ORG')]"
Take Cover and jockey David Allan won the King George Stakes at Glorious Goodwood.,"[('8-1', 'CARDINAL'), ('Washington DC', 'GPE'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('David Griffiths', 'PERSON'), ('2014', 'DATE'), ('Franklin D', 'PERSON'), ('Ryan Moore', 'PERSON'), ('the Betfred Mile', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('20-1', 'CARDINAL'), ('Allan', 'PERSON'), ('Take Cover', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Cornelius Lysaght', 'PERSON'), ('BBC', 'ORG'), ('Take Cover', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('56.86 breathless seconds', 'TIME'), ('Take Cover', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('nine', 'TIME')]",Favourite Take Cover and jockey Aidan O'Brien have won the King George VI and Queen Elizabeth Stakes at Glorious Goodwood.,"[('Take Cover', 'ORG'), (""Aidan O'Brien"", 'PERSON'), ('the King George VI', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Queen Elizabeth Stakes', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Glorious Goodwood', 'FAC')]"
A man has been flown to hospital by a rescue helicopter after falling 25-30 metres from cliffs in the Mournes.,"[('Glen River Valley', 'LOC'), ('Slieve Comedagh', 'GPE'), ('14:00 BST', 'TIME'), ('Sunday', 'DATE'), ('Mourne Mountain Rescue', 'ORG'), ('Belfast', 'GPE')]","A man has been taken to hospital after he and his partner were injured in a fall in the Mourne mountains in County Antrim, the fire service has said.","[('Mourne', 'GPE'), ('County Antrim', 'GPE')]"
Scotland won bronze after coming from behind to beat China at the World Wheelchair Curling Championship in South Korea.,"[('Scottish', 'NORP'), ('Aileen Neilson', 'PERSON'), ('Rob McPherson', 'PERSON'), ('Gregor Ewan', 'PERSON'), ('Hugh Nibloe', 'PERSON'), ('5-4', 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Norway', 'GPE'), ('Russia', 'GPE'), ('Scotland', 'GPE'), ('Saturday', 'DATE')]",Scotland won bronze at the World Wheelchair Curling Championships in Canada on Sunday after coming from behind to beat Canada in the semi-finals in Ottawa.,"[('Scotland', 'GPE'), ('the World Wheelchair Curling Championships', 'EVENT'), ('Canada', 'GPE'), ('Sunday', 'DATE'), ('Canada', 'GPE'), ('Ottawa', 'GPE')]"
A cat that got trapped in a stairlift has been rescued thanks to the dogged determination of an RSPCA inspector.,"[('Maggie May', 'PERSON'), ('Helsington', 'GPE'), ('Kendal', 'GPE'), ('Cumbria', 'GPE'), ('RSPCA', 'ORG'), ('Chris Towler', 'PERSON'), ('Maggie May', 'PERSON'), ('Insp Towler', 'PERSON'), ('Towler', 'PERSON'), ('Maggie May', 'PERSON')]",A cat had to be rescued after it became trapped under a stairlift when its owner went down the stairs and forgot to move the chair it was on.,[]
"The militant group Islamic State is committing war crimes and imposing a ""rule of terror"" in areas it controls in Syria, a UN report says.","[('more than 300', 'CARDINAL'), ('Syria', 'GPE'), ('Iraq', 'GPE'), ('June', 'DATE'), ('UN', 'ORG'), ('Rule of Terror: Living under Isis', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Syria', 'GPE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('UN', 'ORG'), ('Isis', 'LOC'), ('Isil', 'LOC'), ('Syria', 'GPE'), ('Syrian', 'NORP')]","The so-called Islamic State (IS) group has carried out ""brutal"" attacks on civilians in Syria, according to a UN report.","[('Islamic State (IS', 'ORG'), ('Syria', 'GPE'), ('UN', 'ORG')]"
It is considered a virtue in football not to look back - players and managers are often reluctant to reflect on achievements or to dwell on the past.,"[('Chris Coleman', 'PERSON'), ('Wales', 'GPE'), ('the Republic of Ireland', 'GPE'), ('Friday', 'DATE'), ('58 years', 'DATE'), ('Euro 2016', 'EVENT'), ('Wales', 'GPE'), ('Friday', 'DATE'), ('World Cup', 'EVENT'), ('Dublin', 'GPE'), (""next year's"", 'DATE'), ('Russia', 'GPE'), ('Coleman', 'PERSON'), ('France', 'GPE'), ('last summer', 'DATE'), ('Russia', 'GPE'), ('France', 'GPE'), ('Russia', 'GPE')]","Sometimes it is difficult to find the words to describe the feeling of being on the verge of something you have never experienced before, especially when it comes to football.",[]
Why is the art world getting excited about digital currency Bitcoin and its underlying technology blockchain?,"[('Eleesa Dadiani', 'PERSON'), ('London', 'GPE'), ('Cork Street', 'FAC'), ('Georgia', 'GPE'), ('Caucasus', 'LOC'), ('Bitcoin', 'ORG'), ('Formula 1', 'ORG'), ('One', 'CARDINAL'), ('about Â£35,000', 'MONEY'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Cork Street', 'FAC'), ('Bitcoin', 'PRODUCT'), ('Ethereum', 'PRODUCT'), ('Ethereum Classic', 'ORG'), ('Monero', 'PRODUCT')]","The world's first art gallery to accept Bitcoin is opening its doors to the digital currency's growing use in the art world, reports the BBC's Mark Lowen.","[('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Bitcoin', 'ORG'), ('BBC', 'ORG'), ('Mark Lowen', 'PERSON')]"
Politicians in Bath are to launch their latest bid for expansion of one of the city's park-and-ride sites.,"[('250', 'CARDINAL'), ('Newbridge', 'FAC'), ('Lansdown', 'ORG'), ('Liberal Democrat', 'NORP'), ('Bath Transportation Package', 'ORG'), ('870', 'CARDINAL'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Last year', 'DATE'), ('Bath', 'GPE'), ('North East Somerset Council', 'ORG'), ('Bathampton Meadows', 'FAC'), ('27m', 'MONEY'), ('Newbridge', 'GPE'), ('ten', 'CARDINAL'), ('the autumn', 'DATE')]",Plans to increase the number of park-and-ride spaces in Bath have been given the go-ahead by the local authority's cabinet.,"[('Bath', 'GPE')]"
"The Toronto city council has voted to strip Mayor Rob Ford of most of his authority, as the embattled city leader resists growing pressure to step down.","[('Monday', 'DATE'), ('Ford', 'PERSON'), ('Ford', 'PERSON'), ('44', 'DATE'), ('Canada', 'GPE'), ('recent weeks', 'DATE'), ('Ford', 'PERSON'), ('Monday', 'DATE'), ('today', 'DATE'), ('Ford', 'PERSON'), ('Ford', 'PERSON')]","Toronto Mayor Rob Ford has accused the city council of being a ""dictatorship"" after it voted to strip him of most of his powers.","[('Toronto', 'GPE'), ('Rob Ford', 'PERSON')]"
"Alien director Sir Ridley Scott has paid tribute to Swiss artist HR Giger, who has died aged 74 - describing him as ""a true original"".","[('Giger', 'PERSON'), ('Ridley', 'PERSON'), ('Oscar', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('1980', 'DATE'), ('Monday', 'DATE'), ('Zurich', 'GPE'), ('Giger', 'PERSON'), ('Ridley', 'PERSON'), ('Time', 'ORG'), ('Shepperton', 'ORG'), ('Giger', 'PERSON')]","Director Sir Ridley Scott has paid tribute to the Swiss artist H R Giger, who has died at the age of 83, following a fall.","[('Ridley Scott', 'PERSON'), ('Swiss', 'NORP'), ('H R Giger', 'PERSON'), ('the age of 83', 'DATE')]"
Shashank Manohar is set to replace N Srinivasan as chairman of cricket's world governing body for the remainder of his term.,"[('Manohar', 'PERSON'), (""the Board of Control for Cricket in India's"", 'ORG'), ('BCCI', 'ORG'), ('Srinivasan', 'PERSON'), ('ICC', 'ORG'), ('Manohar', 'PERSON'), ('the end of June 2016', 'DATE'), ('Indian', 'NORP'), ('last year', 'DATE'), ('Srinivasan', 'PERSON'), ('70', 'DATE'), ('BCCI', 'ORG'), ('the Supreme Court', 'ORG'), ('last year', 'DATE'), ('Chennai Super Kings', 'ORG'), ('the Indian Premier League', 'ORG'), ('Srinivasan', 'PERSON'), ('Gurunath Meiyapppan', 'PERSON'), ('Chennai', 'GPE'), ('ICC', 'ORG'), ('Manohar', 'PERSON'), ('ICC', 'ORG'), ('BCCI', 'ORG'), ('ICC', 'ORG'), ('BCCI', 'ORG')]",The International Cricket Council (ICC) has confirmed that N Srinivasan has been replaced as its chief executive by Shashank Manohar.,"[('The International Cricket Council (ICC', 'ORG'), ('N Srinivasan', 'PERSON'), ('Shashank Manohar', 'PERSON')]"
"Cigarette packs sold in the EU will have to have bigger health warnings in text and pictures, under new proposals from the EU Commission.","[('75%', 'PERCENT'), ('EU', 'ORG'), ('2001', 'DATE'), ('2014', 'DATE'), ('EU', 'ORG'), ('Tonio Borg', 'PERSON'), ('30%', 'PERCENT'), ('40%', 'PERCENT'), ('Commission', 'ORG'), ('at least 20', 'CARDINAL'), ('Fourteen', 'CARDINAL'), ('EU', 'ORG')]","The European Commission has proposed tougher rules for the packaging of cigarettes, including bigger health warnings and a ban on the use of company logos. and flavours.","[('The European Commission', 'ORG')]"
A judge in Kashmir has rejected prosecution evidence put forward in the trial of a man accused of murdering Guernsey woman Sarah Groves.,"[('Dutch', 'NORP'), ('Richard de Wit', 'PERSON'), ('43', 'DATE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('4 October', 'DATE'), ('Sarah Groves', 'PERSON'), ('April', 'DATE'), ('Srinagar', 'GPE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Sarah', 'PERSON'), ('BBC', 'ORG'), ('Riyaz Masroor', 'PERSON'), ('Masroor', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')]","The trial of a man accused of murdering British backpacker Sarah Groves in Indian-administered Kashmir has been adjourned because of ""inconclusive"" evidence.","[('British', 'NORP'), ('Sarah Groves', 'PERSON'), ('Kashmir', 'LOC')]"
Ivanka Trump has found herself in the midst of a mini-scandal less than a week after her father was elected president.,"[('Trump', 'PERSON'), ('10,000', 'MONEY'), (""Donald Trump's"", 'PERSON'), ('60 Minutes', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Trump', 'PERSON'), ('CBS', 'ORG'), ('20 million', 'CARDINAL'), ('Trump', 'PERSON'), ('5bn', 'MONEY'), ('Indians', 'NORP'), ('10,800', 'MONEY'), ('8,670', 'MONEY'), ('roughly a fifth', 'CARDINAL'), ('US', 'GPE'), ('annual', 'DATE'), ('Trump', 'PERSON'), ('Ivanka Trump', 'PERSON'), ('Abigail Klem', 'PERSON'), ('The New York Times', 'ORG')]","Ivanka Trump, the daughter of US President-elect Donald Trump, has been accused of ""cashing in"" on her father's position.","[('Ivanka Trump', 'PERSON'), ('US', 'GPE'), ('Donald Trump', 'PERSON')]"
"The Welsh Conservative leader has said his AMs have backed him to stay in the role, despite the party's disappointing election result.","[('Andrew RT Davies', 'PERSON'), ('BBC Wales', 'ORG'), ('11', 'CARDINAL'), ('Conservative', 'NORP'), ('AMs', 'ORG'), ('Monday', 'DATE'), ('Tory', 'NORP'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('AMs', 'ORG'), ('Cardiff Bay', 'GPE'), ('5 May', 'DATE'), ('Conservatives', 'NORP'), ('2015', 'DATE'), ('Davies', 'PERSON'), ('Davies', 'PERSON')]","The leader of the Welsh Conservatives has said he will stand down at the end of the assembly election, if there is a ""better alternative who can take us forward"".","[('the Welsh Conservatives', 'NORP')]"
"An Australian couple's deportation is a human rights issue because their seven-year-old son's first language is Gaelic, SNP MP Ian Blackford has said.","[('Brain', 'PERSON'), ('Scotland', 'GPE'), ('2011', 'DATE'), ('UK', 'GPE'), ('Australia', 'GPE'), (""six days'"", 'DATE'), ('Gregg', 'PERSON'), (""Kathryn Brain's"", 'PERSON'), ('Lachlan', 'PERSON'), ('Gaelic', 'LANGUAGE'), ('UK', 'GPE'), ('Dingwall', 'GPE'), ('SNP', 'ORG'), ('Angus Robertson', 'PERSON'), ('George Osborne', 'PERSON'), (""Brains'"", 'PERSON'), ('Robertson', 'PERSON'), ('UK', 'GPE'), ('David Cameron', 'PERSON'), ('Robertson', 'PERSON'), ('Scottish', 'NORP'), ('Scotland', 'GPE'), ('the Home Office', 'ORG'), ('Scottish', 'NORP'), ('the Highlands and Islands', 'LOC')]",An Australian family whose five-year-old son attends a Gaelic-medium school in the Highlands has been told they must leave the UK.,"[('Australian', 'NORP'), ('Highlands', 'LOC'), ('UK', 'GPE')]"
Motherwell feasted on possession against East Stirlingshire but made a meal of scoring goals in their Betfred League Cup tie against the Lowland League side.,"[('nearly an hour', 'TIME'), ('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('Scottish', 'NORP'), ('Marvin Johnson', 'PERSON'), ('Scott McDonald', 'PERSON'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Chris Cadden', 'PERSON'), ('third', 'ORDINAL'), (""Richard Tait's"", 'PERSON'), ('James McFadden', 'PERSON'), ('Motherwell', 'ORG'), ('Stephen Robinson', 'PERSON'), ('Oldham Athletic', 'ORG'), ('summer', 'DATE'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Rangers', 'ORG'), ('Motherwell', 'PERSON'), ('Johnson', 'PERSON'), ('Scott McDonald', 'PERSON'), ('Chris Cadden', 'PERSON'), ('Ben Heneghan', 'PERSON'), ('Johnson', 'PERSON'), ('the first half', 'DATE')]","Motherwell made a winning start to their League Cup campaign with a comfortable victory over League Two side East Stirlingshire, despite being outplayed from start to finish.","[('Motherwell', 'PERSON'), ('League Cup', 'EVENT'), ('League Two', 'FAC'), ('East Stirlingshire', 'GPE')]"
"Last week, Aloisa Elvira de Souza walked into a job centre specialising in finding maids for middle-class families in Brazil.","[('A few years ago', 'DATE'), ('Souza', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('the past 12 years', 'DATE'), ('Sao Paulo', 'GPE'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Souza', 'PERSON'), ('Brazil', 'GPE'), ('more than two decades', 'DATE'), ('The International Monetary Fund (IMF', 'ORG'), ('almost 8%', 'PERCENT'), ('two years', 'DATE'), ('the end of 2016', 'DATE'), ('Brazil', 'GPE'), ('the past decade', 'DATE'), ('one', 'CARDINAL')]","An agency in the Brazilian city of Sao Paulo is looking for a maid for a family of five, and Maria Ines de Souza is one of them.","[('Brazilian', 'NORP'), ('Sao Paulo', 'GPE'), ('five', 'CARDINAL'), ('Maria Ines de Souza', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL')]"
Castleford prop Gadwin Springer has signed a two-year contract extension.,"[('France', 'GPE'), ('the end of 2019', 'DATE'), ('31', 'CARDINAL'), ('Tigers', 'ORG'), ('Catalans', 'NORP'), ('June 2015', 'DATE'), ('French Guiana', 'GPE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('South America', 'LOC'), ('Super League', 'ORG'), ('Catalans', 'NORP'), ('Springer', 'PERSON'), ('Cas', 'PERSON'), ('second', 'ORDINAL')]","Castleford Tigers half-back Matty Springer has signed a new two-year contract with the Super League club, with the option of a further 12 months.","[('Castleford Tigers', 'ORG'), ('Matty Springer', 'PERSON'), ('Super League', 'ORG'), ('a further 12 months', 'DATE')]"
"An attack by the Islamist group al-Shabab in a hotel in the Somali capital Mogadishu has left at least 14 dead, police say.","[('Naso-Hablod', 'GPE'), ('Al-Shabab', 'ORG'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Ali Mohamud', 'PERSON'), ('Associated Press', 'ORG'), ('at least four', 'CARDINAL'), ('Mohamed Hussein', 'PERSON'), ('Naso-Hablod', 'GPE'), ('Mogadishu', 'GPE')]","At least 20 people have been killed in an attack by al-Shabab militants on a hotel in the Somali capital, Mogadishu, officials say.","[('At least 20', 'CARDINAL'), ('al-Shabab', 'ORG'), ('Somali', 'NORP'), ('Mogadishu', 'GPE')]"
A man has been stabbed in the face in an attack in Belfast city centre.,"[('Alfred Street', 'FAC'), ('Sussex Place', 'FAC'), ('02:00 BST', 'TIME'), ('Sunday', 'DATE'), ('30s', 'DATE'), ('about 5\'8"" (172cm)', 'QUANTITY'), ('Ormeau Avenue', 'FAC'), ('101', 'CARDINAL')]",A man has been left with serious facial injuries after he was attacked by a man in the early hours of the morning in Londonderry.,"[('the early hours of the morning', 'TIME'), ('Londonderry', 'GPE')]"
German Phil Bauhaus claimed his first World Tour win with victory on stage five of the Criterium du Dauphine.,"[('Sunweb', 'ORG'), ('22', 'DATE'), ('Frenchmen', 'NORP'), ('Arnaud Demare', 'PERSON'), ('Bryan Coquard', 'PERSON'), ('175.5km', 'TIME'), ('La Tour-de-Salvagny', 'FAC'), ('Macon', 'GPE'), ('Belgium', 'GPE'), ('Thomas de Gendt', 'PERSON'), ('27 seconds', 'TIME'), ('Australian', 'NORP'), ('Richie Porte', 'PERSON'), ('Britain', 'GPE'), ('Chris Froome', 'PERSON'), ('Team Sky', 'ORG'), ('sixth', 'DATE'), ('one minute four seconds', 'TIME'), ('Thursday', 'DATE'), ('the final three days', 'DATE'), ('Bauhaus', 'PERSON'), (""the Giro d'Italia"", 'ORG'), ('six', 'CARDINAL'), ('147.5km', 'CARDINAL'), ('Villars-les-Dombes', 'GPE'), ('La Motte-Servolex', 'FAC'), ('Dauphine', 'FAC'), ('Sunday', 'DATE'), (""next month's"", 'DATE'), ('Tour de France', 'EVENT'), ('Froome', 'PERSON'), ('Tour', 'EVENT'), ('fourth', 'ORDINAL'), ('this summer', 'DATE'), ('2013', 'DATE'), ('2015', 'DATE')]",Germany's Thomas Bauhaus won the fifth stage of the Criterium du Dauphine to move up to fourth in the race.,"[('Germany', 'GPE'), ('Thomas Bauhaus', 'PERSON'), ('fifth', 'ORDINAL'), ('the Criterium du Dauphine', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('fourth', 'ORDINAL')]"
Aston Villa midfielder Leandro Bacuna has been banned for six games following an altercation with an assistant referee in their home win over Derby.,"[('the fourth minute', 'TIME'), (""the end of last Saturday's"", 'DATE'), ('Bacuna', 'PERSON'), ('25', 'DATE'), ('Curacao', 'GPE'), ('25', 'CARDINAL'), ('Villa', 'PERSON'), ('Netherlands', 'GPE'), ('Groningen', 'GPE'), ('the summer of 2013', 'DATE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Villa', 'PERSON'), ('Steve Bruce', 'PERSON'), ('BBC WM Sport', 'ORG'), ('95.6', 'CARDINAL'), ('Bacuna', 'PERSON'), ('the last minute', 'TIME'), ('Bacuna', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Tuesday', 'DATE'), ('Bristol City', 'GPE')]",Aston Villa midfielder Ruben Bacuna has been banned for two matches after admitting a charge of violent conduct following his red card against Burnley.,"[('Aston Villa', 'ORG'), ('Ruben Bacuna', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Burnley', 'ORG')]"
A jury in the United States has ruled that the writers of Blurred Lines - one of the best-selling singles of all time - copied a Marvin Gaye track.,"[('Los Angeles', 'GPE'), ('2013', 'DATE'), ('Pharrell Williams', 'PERSON'), ('Robin Thicke', 'PERSON'), ('Gaye', 'PERSON'), ('1977', 'DATE'), ('Got To Give It Up', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('$7.3m (Â£4.8m', 'MONEY'), ('Thicke', 'PERSON'), ('Williams', 'PERSON'), ('Gaye', 'PERSON'), ('Rolling Stone', 'ORG'), ('Blurred Lines', 'ORG'), ('Blurred Lines', 'ORG'), ('Richard Busch', 'PERSON'), ('Gaye', 'PERSON'), ('April 1984', 'DATE'), ('Nona', 'PERSON'), ('Frankie', 'PERSON'), ('Marvin Gaye III', 'PERSON'), ('Thicke', 'PERSON'), ('Williams', 'PERSON'), ('2013', 'DATE'), ('Nona', 'PERSON'), ('Pharrell Williams', 'PERSON'), ('Robin Thi', 'PERSON')]",The family of Marvin Gaye has won a legal battle against the makers of Blurred Lines over a song he wrote and performed with the late singer.,"[('Marvin Gaye', 'PERSON'), ('Blurred Lines', 'ORG')]"
"Ex-Premier League players Carlos Tevez, Dirk Kuyt and Gabriel Heinze have been named by hackers Fancy Bears as three of the footballers cleared to use banned medicines at the 2010 World Cup.","[('25', 'CARDINAL'), ('South Africa', 'GPE'), ('Russian', 'NORP'), ('160', 'CARDINAL'), ('2015', 'DATE'), ('Four', 'CARDINAL'), ('UK Anti-Doping (Ukad', 'ORG'), ('Three', 'CARDINAL'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Fancy Bears', 'ORG'), ('Tevez', 'PERSON'), ('33', 'DATE'), ('Manchester City', 'GPE'), ('the World Cup', 'EVENT'), ('2010', 'DATE'), ('Manchester United', 'ORG'), ('the previous year', 'DATE'), ('Argentina', 'GPE'), ('Heinze', 'PERSON'), ('39', 'DATE'), ('French', 'NORP'), ('Marseille', 'PERSON'), ('three seasons', 'DATE'), ('Old Trafford', 'GPE'), ('Kuyt', 'PERSON'), ('37', 'DATE'), ('Liverpool', 'ORG'), (""the Football Association's"", 'ORG'), ('Jenni Kennedy', 'PERSON'), ('Fifa', 'ORG'), ('FA', 'ORG')]","Fancy Bears has released details of how Carlos Tevez, Dirk Heinze and Dirk Kuyt were allowed to use performance-enhancing drugs during the 2010 World Cup.","[('Carlos Tevez', 'PERSON'), ('Dirk Heinze', 'PERSON'), ('Dirk Kuyt', 'PERSON'), ('2010', 'DATE'), ('World Cup', 'EVENT')]"
Wasps secured a bonus-point victory at Twickenham to consign London Irish to a fifth Premiership defeat of the season.,"[(""Frank Halai's"", 'PERSON'), ('Wasps', 'ORG'), ('11-8', 'CARDINAL'), ('Johnny Williams', 'PERSON'), ('Exiles', 'ORG'), ('Elliot Daly', 'PERSON'), ('21-8', 'CARDINAL'), ('Irish', 'NORP'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Williams', 'PERSON'), ('Wasps', 'ORG'), ('Thomas Young', 'PERSON'), ('Halai', 'PERSON'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Newcastle', 'ORG'), ('Sale', 'ORG'), ('Saturday', 'DATE'), ('Irish', 'NORP'), ('Premiership', 'ORG'), ('the opening half', 'DATE'), ('London Irish', 'ORG'), ('Daly', 'PERSON'), ('nine minutes into the second half', 'TIME'), ('Wasps', 'ORG'), ('Williams', 'PERSON'), ('Topsy Ojo', 'PERSON'), ('Exiles', 'ORG'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('the last 10 minutes', 'TIME'), (""Wasps'"", 'PERSON'), ('Midlands', 'ORG'), ('fourth', 'ORDINAL'), ('Premiership', 'ORG'), ('London Irish', 'ORG'), ('Tom Coventry', 'PERSON'), ('BBC Radio Berkshire', 'ORG')]","Wasps moved up to fourth in the Premiership with a hard-fought victory over London Irish at the Ricoh Arena, despite a second-half fightback from the Exiles.","[('Wasps', 'ORG'), ('fourth', 'ORDINAL'), ('Premiership', 'ORG'), ('London Irish', 'ORG'), ('the Ricoh Arena', 'FAC'), ('Exiles', 'ORG')]"
The Great North Air Ambulance Service (GNAAS) has opened a base at Newcastle International Airport.,"[('Tyne and Wear', 'GPE'), ('Northumberland', 'GPE'), ('Durham Tees Valley Airport', 'FAC'), ('Kevin Hodgson', 'PERSON'), ('GNAAS', 'ORG'), ('the North East', 'LOC')]",The Great North Air Ambulance Service (GNAAS) is to move its base from Newcastle Airport to Gateshead Airport from 1 July.,"[('The Great North Air Ambulance Service (GNAAS)', 'ORG'), ('Newcastle Airport', 'FAC'), ('Gateshead Airport', 'FAC'), ('1 July', 'DATE')]"
"Four homeless street drinkers have been found guilty of killing a ""vulnerable"" man who was attacked in his own home.","[('David Miller', 'PERSON'), ('56', 'DATE'), ('Northampton', 'GPE'), ('last June', 'DATE'), ('Michael Hallett', 'PERSON'), ('37', 'DATE'), ('Joseph Catlin', 'PERSON'), ('30', 'DATE'), ('Zena Kane', 'PERSON'), ('35', 'DATE'), ('Ian Cuthbertson', 'PERSON'), ('49', 'DATE'), ('seven and a half years', 'DATE'), ('Northamptonshire', 'GPE'), ('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('Miller', 'PERSON'), ('Northampton Crown Court', 'ORG'), ('Miller', 'PERSON'), ('Patterdale Walk', 'FAC'), ('Hallett', 'PERSON'), ('at least 23 years', 'DATE'), ('Catlin 18', 'PERSON'), ('Kane', 'PERSON'), ('20', 'CARDINAL'), ('Miller', 'PERSON'), ('Northampton Crown Court', 'ORG'), ('David', 'PERSON')]","Three men and a woman have been jailed for the ""horrific"" murder of a man whose body was found covered in porridge oats.","[('Three', 'CARDINAL')]"
Connacht's hopes of securing a home semi-final in the Pro12 suffered a blow as they were shocked in Treviso.,"[('Rory Parata', 'PERSON'), ('Fionn Carr', 'PERSON'), ('Connacht', 'PERSON'), ('Treviso', 'PERSON'), ('Jayden Hayward', 'PERSON'), ('Luca Morisi', 'PERSON'), ('Braam Steyn', 'PERSON'), ('Connacht', 'ORG'), ('14-12', 'CARDINAL'), ('Treviso', 'PERSON'), ('45 minutes', 'TIME'), ('Peter Robb', 'PERSON'), ('Connacht', 'ORG'), ('Hayward', 'PERSON'), ('Treviso', 'GPE'), ('European', 'NORP'), ('Champions Cup', 'EVENT'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Zebre', 'ORG'), ('11th', 'ORDINAL'), ('Connacht', 'ORG'), ('11', 'CARDINAL'), ('Scarlets', 'ORG'), ('Glasgow', 'GPE'), ('Zebre', 'PERSON'), ('Friday', 'DATE'), ('Irish', 'NORP'), ('third', 'ORDINAL'), (""Next weekend's"", 'DATE'), ('Galway', 'GPE'), ('Connacht', 'GPE'), ('Glasgow', 'GPE'), ('Friday', 'DATE'), ('Connacht', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('the opening 14 minutes', 'TIME'), ('Parata', 'PERSON'), ('Carr', 'PERSON')]",Connacht missed out on a home Pro12 semi-final as they were beaten by Treviso at the Stadio Olimpico.,"[('Connacht', 'PERSON'), ('Pro12', 'ORG'), ('Treviso', 'GPE'), ('the Stadio Olimpico', 'FAC')]"
"""Long-term youth unemployment is a national disgrace that can leave a life-time scar.""","[('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('UK', 'GPE'), ('the Confederation of British Industry', 'ORG'), ('CBI', 'ORG'), ('John Cridland', 'PERSON'), ('ONS', 'ORG'), ('188,000', 'CARDINAL'), ('18 to 24-year-olds', 'CARDINAL'), ('more than 12 months', 'DATE'), ('10%', 'PERCENT'), ('four years', 'DATE'), ('nearly 25%', 'PERCENT'), ('Matty Finnigan', 'PERSON'), ('23', 'DATE'), ('Lowestoft', 'GPE'), ('around three years', 'DATE'), ('the last few months', 'DATE'), ('Tomorrow', 'DATE')]","Unemployment among 18 to 24-year-olds in the UK is at its highest level for more than a decade, according to the Office for National Statistics (ONS).","[('18 to 24-year-olds', 'DATE'), ('UK', 'GPE'), ('more than a decade', 'DATE'), ('the Office for National Statistics', 'ORG'), ('ONS', 'ORG')]"
Votes cast at this year's Australia election will come from as far away as Antarctica.,"[('More than 70', 'CARDINAL'), ('Australia', 'GPE'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('Antarctic', 'LOC'), ('Malcolm Turnbull', 'PERSON'), ('Bill Shorten', 'PERSON'), ('Saturday', 'DATE'), ('as low as minus 40C', 'CARDINAL'), ('about six months of the year', 'DATE'), ('the Australian Antarctic Division', 'ORG')]","Voters in the Antarctic have been able to cast their ballots in Australia's general election for the first time in more than a decade, the country's electoral office says.","[('Antarctic', 'LOC'), ('Australia', 'GPE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('more than a decade', 'DATE')]"
"Panama has agreed to transfer 3,800 Cubans hoping to reach the United States to a town in northern Mexico.","[('Cubans', 'NORP'), ('Panama', 'GPE'), ('months', 'DATE'), ('US', 'GPE'), ('Panama', 'GPE'), ('daily', 'DATE'), ('Ciudad Juarez', 'GPE'), ('Monday', 'DATE'), ('Panama', 'GPE'), ('March', 'DATE'), ('Panamanian', 'NORP'), ('Chiriqui province', 'GPE'), ('Cubans', 'NORP'), ('the United States', 'GPE'), ('Last year', 'DATE'), ('Costa Rica', 'GPE'), ('Nicaragua', 'GPE'), ('Panama', 'GPE'), ('Cubans', 'NORP'), ('Panama', 'GPE'), ('South American', 'NORP'), ('Central America', 'LOC'), ('US', 'GPE'), ('Between January and March', 'DATE'), ('Costa Rica', 'GPE'), ('thousand', 'CARDINAL')]","Hundreds of Cuban migrants stranded in Panama are to be allowed to fly to the US city of Ciudad Juarez in Mexico, officials say.","[('Hundreds', 'CARDINAL'), ('Cuban', 'NORP'), ('Panama', 'GPE'), ('US', 'GPE'), ('Ciudad Juarez', 'GPE'), ('Mexico', 'GPE')]"
The governing body of showjumping in the UK has spoken out about a decision to overlook Scott Brash for BBC Sports Personality of the Year.,"[('30-year-old', 'DATE'), ('Peebles', 'GPE'), ('September', 'DATE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('1m Euros', 'MONEY'), ('Â£725,000', 'MONEY'), ('British Showjumping', 'ORG'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Sports Personality of Year', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('more than 17,000', 'CARDINAL'), ('Brash', 'PERSON'), ('the London Olympics', 'EVENT'), ('2012', 'DATE'), ('This year', 'DATE'), ('Grand Prix', 'EVENT'), ('Geneva', 'GPE'), ('Aachen', 'GPE'), ('Calgary', 'GPE'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('British Showjumping', 'ORG'), ('London', 'GPE'), ('2012', 'DATE'), (""Scott Brash's"", 'PERSON'), ('Scott', 'PERSON')]",Olympic showjumping gold medallist Scott Brash has failed to make the shortlist for the BBC Sports Personality of the Year award.,"[('Olympic', 'EVENT'), ('Scott Brash', 'PERSON'), ('BBC Sports Personality of the Year', 'WORK_OF_ART')]"
A number of Northern Ireland fans have had their dreams of watching their team in the last 16 of the Euros shattered after being left stranded at Belfast International Airport.,"[('Gatwick', 'GPE'), ('Easyjet', 'ORG'), ('20:00 BST', 'TIME'), ('Friday', 'DATE'), ('Paris', 'GPE'), ('160', 'CARDINAL'), ('Dozens', 'CARDINAL'), ('Easyjet', 'ORG'), ('Banbridge', 'GPE'), ('Alan Hylands', 'PERSON'), ('Paris', 'GPE'), ('about midnight', 'TIME'), ('Hylands', 'PERSON'), ('Lille', 'GPE'), ('Paris', 'GPE'), ('Northern Ireland', 'GPE')]",A group of Northern Ireland fans who were due to travel to France for Euro 2016 have been left stranded in the UK after their flight was cancelled.,"[('Northern Ireland', 'GPE'), ('France', 'GPE'), ('Euro 2016', 'EVENT'), ('UK', 'GPE')]"
Uruguay has unveiled a plan to allow state-controlled sales of marijuana to fight a rise in drug-related crime.,"[('Defence', 'ORG'), ('Eleuterio Fernandez Huidobro', 'PERSON'), ('Fernandez Huidobro', 'PERSON'), ('Uruguay', 'GPE'), ('Uruguay', 'GPE'), ('BBC', 'ORG')]",The Uruguayan government has introduced a bill that would ban the sale of marijuana to anyone under the age of 18. and ban the possession of small amounts of the drug.,"[('Uruguayan', 'NORP'), ('the age of 18.', 'DATE')]"
A cannabis farm with a street value of £2m has been uncovered at a property in Liverpool following a police raid.,"[('531', 'CARDINAL'), ('Rockfield Road', 'FAC'), ('Anfield', 'GPE'), ('11:00 GMT', 'TIME'), ('Tuesday', 'DATE'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('annual', 'DATE'), ('about £2m', 'MONEY')]","More than 500 cannabis plants have been found in the basement of a house in Merseyside, police have said, in what is believed to be the largest illegal cannabis farm in the UK.","[('More than 500', 'CARDINAL'), ('Merseyside', 'GPE'), ('UK', 'GPE')]"
"The funeral of Deborah, the Dowager Duchess of Devonshire, has taken place on the Chatsworth estate.","[('Chatsworth House', 'FAC'), (""St Peter's Church"", 'ORG'), ('Edensor', 'GPE'), ('The Prince of Wales', 'PERSON'), ('Mitford', 'PERSON'), ('94', 'DATE'), ('earlier this week', 'DATE'), ('the Duchess of Cornwall', 'PERSON'), ('More than 600', 'CARDINAL'), ('hundreds', 'CARDINAL'), ('Cavendish', 'PERSON'), ('Chatsworth Garden', 'FAC'), ('Aleena NaylorBBC', 'PERSON'), ('Radio Derby', 'ORG'), (""Elvis Presley's"", 'PERSON')]",The funeral of the Dowager Duchess of Devonshire has taken place in the Derbyshire village where she was born and lived for most of her life.,"[('the Dowager Duchess of Devonshire', 'GPE'), ('Derbyshire', 'GPE')]"
"Fast bowler Katherine Brunt has been named in England's Women's World Twenty20 squad, despite a back injury.","[('Lauren Winfield', 'PERSON'), ('T20', 'EVENT'), ('South Africa', 'GPE'), ('Brunt', 'PERSON'), ('30', 'DATE'), ('T20s', 'PRODUCT'), ('South Africa', 'GPE'), ('one-day', 'DATE'), ('Natasha Farrant', 'PERSON'), ('ICC', 'ORG'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Mark Robinson', 'PERSON'), ('Tash', 'PERSON'), ('Sri Lanka', 'GPE'), ('Christmas', 'EVENT'), ('England', 'GPE'), ('2009', 'DATE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Bangladesh', 'GPE'), ('Bangalore', 'GPE'), ('17 March', 'DATE'), ('India', 'GPE'), ('West Indies', 'GPE'), ('Pakistan', 'GPE'), ('England', 'GPE'), ('Tammy Beaumont', 'PERSON'), ('Kent', 'GPE'), ('Katherine Brunt', 'PERSON'), ('Yorkshire', 'GPE'), ('Charlotte Edwards', 'PERSON'), ('Kent', 'GPE'), ('Georgia Elwiss', 'PERSON'), ('Sussex', 'GPE'), ('Natasha Farr', 'PERSON')]",Yorkshire all-rounder Katherine Brunt has been left out of England's squad for the ICC Women's World Twenty20 in India in March.,"[('Yorkshire', 'GPE'), ('Katherine Brunt', 'PERSON'), ('England', 'GPE'), (""the ICC Women's World Twenty20"", 'EVENT'), ('India', 'GPE'), ('March', 'DATE')]"
Have you heard of fidget spinners?,"[('4 May 2017', 'DATE'), ('07:16 BST', 'TIME'), ('Ricky', 'PERSON')]","They're the latest thing in school playgrounds, but do you think they're good for you or are they just a bit too much fun?",[]
